斯坦福大学
> Stanford University.
欢迎来到CS193P课程 2013-14秋季第16讲
> Okay, well welcome to lecture 16 of Stanford CS193P fall of 2013-14.
今天 我们将谈到最后的segue
So today we are going to talk about the last of the segues,
也就是modal segue(模态segue)
which is modal segues
还有一种相关的segue
and their kind of related segue
也就是unwind segue(解开segue)
which is unwinding segues.
模态segue其实很简单
Okay these can be a little, modal segue's really easy.
unwind可能有些让人困扰
The unwinding, you know, can be a little confusing
但愿通过幻灯片讲解和demo演示 你们能懂
and so hopefully both the combination of the slides and the demo will get you there.
不过理解这些很重要 这些unwind segue
But it's an important one to understand, these unwinding segues.
我们还会简要谈到文本框
Also, briefly we're going to talk about text fields
这方面我还没讲过 还有警告
which we haven't covered yet and also alert
以及动作表单 然后我将进行demo
and action sheet and then I'm going to do this demo.
有时间再讲摄像头
It says camera time permitting,
可惜我们几乎肯定没时间
but we will definitely not have time for that.
这将是我们下周三的内容
That's what we'll start off on Wednesday with.
好 模态视图控制器
All right, modal view controllers,
这是另一种segue的方式
this is another way to segue,
将视图控制器放到屏幕上的另一种方式
another way to put a view controller on screen.
在导航控制器中 你们已经知道
You already know about popovers and you know about push segues
popover和push segue
in a navigation controller.
这里是又一种方式 叫作模态视图控制器
So this is another way called modal view controllers.
模态视图控制器是将视图控制器放到屏幕上时
And a modal view controller is a way of putting a view controller on screen
它会占据整个屏幕
where it takes over the entire screen.
在这个视图控制器处在屏幕上时
For the lifetime of that view controller being on screen,
它会占据整个屏幕
it's in charge of the entire screen.
在iPhone上 占据方式是覆盖整块屏幕
On the iPhone it takes over the entire screen by covering the entire screen.
在iPad上 它通常以弹窗形式占据整块屏幕
On the iPad it usually takes over by being in a popover.
我们知道 弹窗本质上是模态的
And as we know, popovers are essentially modal.
它们处在一种模式中
They're in a mode.
弹窗出现时 其它一切都会变得灰暗
When your popover comes up, everything else is kind of dark gray.
点别的地方时 弹窗就会消失
And if you click on anything else, the popover goes away, right?
它其实也是一种占据
So it's essentially taking over as well.
模态视图控制器是一种将视图控制器放到屏幕上
So modal view controllers are a way to put things up
并占据整个屏幕的方式
on screen that takes over.
我们来看看这个的iPhone版本
So let's look at the iPhone version of this.
这是一个小demo
Here's a little demo of it.
这是联系人app
So this is the contacts app
这里有我的联系人名录
and you can see I've got my contacts there,
如果我想在这里加一个联系人 我该怎么做
my winning contacts, and so what if I want to add another contact here?
假设我要添加Montay Ball或是谁
Let's say I want to add Montay Ball [assumed spelling] or something like that.
如何做到呢
How would I do that?
我会点右上角的那个加号
Well I would press that little plus up there in the corner,
点加号后会怎样
and what would happen when I press plus?
我们看看
So let's watch.
点加号 一整个新的视图控制器会滑入
So I hit plus, and a whole new view controller slides in
完全占据屏幕
and completely takes over the screen.
这不是push
Now this was not a push.
这个取消按钮并不是回退按钮
Okay, that cancel button there, that's not a back button.
它实际占据了整个屏幕
It actually took over the whole screen.
只是取消碰巧处在回退相同的位置
Now cancel happens to be in the same place that back would be,
这是很不错的UI一致性
which is kind of decent UI consistency there,
不过这里使用的是不同机制
but it's a different, totally different modal mechanism.
这个模态视图控制器占据了屏幕
So not only, so we have this modal view controller that's taking over the screen.
这里还有另一个按钮 说添加照片
And for example, there's another button on this one, add photo,
这就会使用另一个模态视图控制器 覆盖这个屏幕
which uses another modal view controller and covers this guy's screen.
再看点击添加照片时会发生什么
So let's watch what happens when we hit add photo.
这又覆盖了整个屏幕
See? That covers up the whole screen again.
这发生了两层模态segue
So now we have two levels of modal segues happening here.
这不是push 没有回退按钮
And again it's not a push, there's no back button.
这里 取消按钮处在右侧
In this one the cancel button happens to be on the right.
我运行的这个设备上没有任何照片和视频可供选择
And I don't have any photos or videos to choose here on this device that I'm running on,
但你可以看到 没有回退按钮
but you can see no back button there.
如果我点取消
Now, when I cancel, okay
这个模态视图控制器会消失 看看
and this modal view controller goes away, watch what happens.
它会消失
It disappears.
我回到了之前的模态视图控制器
I go back to the previous modal obviously.
然后如果我取消这个
And then if I cancel this modal,
那样我就又会回到再之前
okay, then I'll go back to the previous one from that.
模态占据屏幕 直到你点完成
So modal takes over the screen until it's, you hit either done
或是取消 这时它就会消失
or cancel or something and then it goes away and goes back
并回到你原来的地方
to where you were, exactly where you were.
很简单 我只是想保证你们理解了
So, it's pretty straightforward but just want
我们能用模态视图控制器做些什么
to make sure you understand what we're doing here with modal view controllers.
下面是需要考虑的一些东西
Now some things to think about,
模态segue会让用户有些失去方向
modal segues can be a little disorienting to the user
他们本来是在很好的app中 本来很舒服
because they're in their nice app, they're really comfy,
之后突然间 整个屏幕都被别的东西所占据
and then all the sudden their whole screen is completely taken over by something else.
他们会想 哦 这是什么
And like whoa, what's this? Now,
在合适的地方使用模态视图控制器倒还没问题
you know, if you're using modal view controllers in the proper places, it's okay.
用户能接受
The user's fine with that.
例如联系人 添加联系人 他们能够很理解
Like the contacts, they're adding a new contact, they understand okay well I have
我需要填入这个联系人的信息 然后点完成
to completely specify this contact before I say done,
否则这里我什么事情都做不了
so I kind of can't do anything else anyway until I'm done.
但模态视图控制器有可能会被滥用
But modal view controllers can be overused.
很多学生都在过度使用它
I see students overusing it a lot.
他们总是喜欢说
They're just kind of like oh,
我需要把这个视图控制器放到屏幕上
well I need to put the view controller on the screen
就用模态视图控制器吧
so I'll just put it up modally.
其实有时 push到屏幕上会更好
And, whereas it might be better to push it onto screen if it's,
例如总需要回退的时候
if going back makes sense at all times.
如果push什么东西 总回退没有意义
If you push something and it doesn't make sense to go back
那使用push可能就不是正确的方式了
at all times, then push is probably not right.
不过有时你要问自己 我能否像这样设计UI
But then you might ask yourself, can I design my UI
在导航控制器中总让它回退 而没有问题
so it is always okay to go back, right? You know, in a navigation controller.
模态视图控制器很容易被滥用
So modal view controllers tend to get overused.
用户有时会被它们弄得一头雾水 因此 请小心使用
Users can sometimes by disoriented by them so use them with care.
如何设置一个模态segue呢
How do we set a modal segue up?
很简单
Super simple.
到故事板 找到你想要模态segue到的视图控制器
Got our story board, have the view controller you want to modal segue to,
我们只需要control拖动
we just control drag.
control拖动 问你要怎样的segue
Control drag, and when it says what kind of segue do you want
你选modal 而不是原来的push
you say modal instead of push for example.
这样就能设置好了
And bam, that's all that's necessary to set it up.
这是一个常规的segue
And it's a normal segue
和其它segue一样需要准备
so you're going to prepare for segue just like any other segues.
把它放到屏幕上时 情况同push很像
It's very, when it comes to pushing it,
or you know not pushing it, putting it on screen, it's very much like pushing.
你们会对此非常习惯
So it's very, you'll be very used to that.
你也可以手动进行segue 就像上周我们讲的
It can be manually segued to just like we talked about last week.
你甚至可以通过创建视图控制器
You can even put them up by creating view controllers
把它们放到屏幕上 不过课上我没讲这个
and put them on screen but we don't really talk about that in this class
因为这是很过时的做法
because that's really old style way of doing things.
我们一般是在故事板中control拖动来设置segue
We do things in storyboard and we control drag to set up segues.
它也需要准备 怎样准备呢
So it's normal to prepare. What does a prepare look like?
同其它prepareForSegue类似
It looks like any other prepare for segue, right?
你得到目标控制器 检查标识符
You get the destination controller, maybe check the identifier.
看它是什么类
You see what class it is.
然后你再设置你的…
You know you set up your des- your,
通过传入视图控制器想要的公共API来做准备
you prepare by passing whatever public API that view controller wants.
下面这里是模态segue变得有趣的地方
Okay now here's where modal segues get interesting though.
也就是接收回复
That's hearing back okay?
模态segue做了什么事情以后
So a modal segue has gone off and done something
例如在联系人app中创建了一个新联系人
like created a new contact in your contact app,
这时 联系人app中
and now the contacts app,
发起segue的视图控制器希望收到回复
you know the view controller that put it up wants to hear back.
你刚创建的联系人是什么
Okay well what was that contact you just created?
接收回复很有趣 这是另一种segue
Okay so this hearing back is kind of the interesting yet another kind of segue.
我们将这称作unwind segue
This hearing back we call these unwind segues.
unwind segue是说 你回给发起你的人
An unwind segue means you're going back to someone who put you up.
有人把你放到屏幕上
Someone who put you on screen.
一个视图控制器把另一个放到屏幕上
We call a view controller that puts another view controller
所谓presenting view controller
on screen, a presenting view controller
它呈现(present)出另一个视图控制器
because it's presenting this other view controller.
unwind segue会回到这个presenting视图控制器
So an unwind segue, you're going back to someone who presented to you.
unwind segue也只能回到presenting视图控制器
Unwind segues can only go back to someone who presented you.
不能unwind到某个非presenting视图控制器
You can't unwind to someone else who didn't present you.
不过在模态引出模态再引出模态的情况下
But in the case where we had modal and then that modal brought up another modal,
你可以一次解开两层
you can unwind two levels at once.
解开可以是到
Okay so you can unwind to anybody
直接或间接present出你的人
who presented you either directly or indirectly.
unwind segue最有趣的一点是
Most interesting thing about unwind segues,
只有这一种segue
they're the only kind of segue
不创建一个新的视图控制器
that doesn't create a new view controller.
其它segue 无论是push 是modal 还是replace
Every other segue-- pushing, modal, replace--
都总会创建另外一个视图控制器
all these segues always create another view controller.
每次都会从头实例化一个
They instantiate one from scratch, every time.
每次在导航控制器中push时
Okay every time you push in a navigation controller,
你都会得到一个新视图控制器
you get a new view controller.
每次modal segue 你也会得到新的
Every time you modally segue, you get a new one.
unwind segue不会这样做 因为它会unwind回
Unwinds obviously don't do that because they're unwinding back
present出你的那个
to someone who presented you.
这显然存在
They obviously already exist.
理解我说的吗
Does that make sense? See what I'm saying?
unwind segue这样看有点古怪
So it's kind of a-- unwind is kind of a weird segue in that way.
它总是会回到已经存在的视图控制器
It always goes back to somebody who already exists.
通常而言 unwind会和modal一同使用
Normally this unwinding is used with modal.
其实它也可以同push一起用
It actually can be used with pushing though.
你可以push push push
You could push and push and push
然后一直unwind回顶部
and then unwind all the way back up to the top.
unwind可以被用在导航控制器中
Okay so unwinding can be used inside navigation controller,
不过最常用的还是modal控制器
but most often probably used in modal controller.
我们来谈谈unwind 以及如何设置
Okay so let's talk about unwinding and how we set that up
如何让它工作 毕竟我说了
and how we make it work because it's a little, again,
它有点让人困扰
like I say it's a little disorienting
因为它没有作为图像显示在故事板中
because it's graphically not shown in the storyboard
同其它segue不一样
in the same way as other segues.
没有线画在那里
There's not the line being drawn.
不过关于unwind segue最重要的一点
But the way you set it up, and the most important thing about an unwind segue
在于指定动作方法
is to specify the action method
这会在presenting视图控制器中被调用
that's going to get called in the presenting view controller--
present出这些东西的那个控制器
the one that's presenting these guys--
unwind时有些方法需要在这其中得到调用
some method has to be called in them when you unwind.
这种方法是一种IBAction
That kind of method, it's an IB action, right?
这是Xcode特别注意的一种东西
It's the kind of thing that Xcode is, pays special attention to.
看起来像是一个目标动作方法
So it looks kind of like a target action method,
不过弄对参数非常重要
but the argument is very important to get right.
这是一个UIStoryboardSegue
It's a UI storyboard segue.
这是因为 这个unwind发生时 这个方法会被调用
That's because when this unwind happens, this method's going to get called
而且它会把unwind segue传给你
and it's going to pass you the unwind segue.
正在发生的segue本身会被传给你
The segue itself that is happening is going to be passed to you.
看这个segue 你可以弄清
And when you look in that segue, you can for example find
这个unwind的来源在哪
out who's the source of this unwind.
也就是你present的东西
That's going to be the thing you presented or the thing
或是一直present下去的东西
that you presented that somebody else presented or presented down the way,
这就是源视图控制器
that's going to be the source view controller.
这是我们唯一考虑segue的源视图控制器的情况
So this is the only case where we've looked at the segue's source view controller.
我们一般只看segue的目标
Usually we're looking at the segue's destination.
但这里 unwind segue的目标会接收这个信息
But in this case the unwind segue destination is receiving this message
我们于是就能知道来源在哪
so it knows who it is, and so it's looking at the source.
显然 这个segue方法的第一行
Okay so obviously the first line in a segue method
通常都是 我从哪里unwind来的
like this is usually who's unwi- who am I unwinding from.
知道从哪unwind来后
Now that you know who you're unwinding from, you could ask
你可以问它 例如添加联系人视图控制器
that thing, like the contact, the add contact view controller,
你添加的联系人是谁
what was the contact you added.
你刚unwind给我
You just unwound to me.
显然你添加了联系人
Obviously you've chose your contact.
你添加的联系人是谁
What was the contact you added?
这样你就得到了联系人 然后添加
And so now you've got the contact, you could add it
到联系人列表 或是做别的什么
to the list of contacts or whatever you want to do.
创建这个方法是最重要的事
So creating that method is the most important thing to do,
仅仅是这个方法的创建
and just the very creation of that method
就会自动让Xcode意识到
will automatically make Xcode realize
你可以unwind到那个视图控制器
that you can unwind to that view controller.
如果视图控制器有这种方法 IBAction
If a view controller has this kind of method, IB action,
任何名称 取一个UIStoryboardSegue
any name takes a UI Storyboard segue,
那个视图控制器现在就可以被unwind到了
that view controller can now be unwound to.
那个视图控制器present出的任何视图控制器
So any view controller that that view controller presents
能够unwind回它
can unwind back to it.
如何设置这种unwind segue呢
Okay so how do you set up that unwind?
这有点奇特
Okay this is a little odd.
在添加联系人的视图控制器中
In the, let's say, add contact view controller,
模态方式present的那个 它会有一个按钮
the one that's being presented modally, it might have a button
说完成 或是保存新联系人 或创建新联系人
in there like done or save new contact or create new contact.
这个按钮 实际会开启这个unwind segue
That button, okay, really wants to start this unwind segue.
但你不能从那个按钮control拖动回
But you can't control drag from that button all the way back
有这个方法的原来那个视图控制器
to the other view controller that has this method.
你可能认为你能 但你不能
You'd think you could, but you can't.
你应从那个按钮control拖动到下面那个绿色小按钮
Instead, you control drag from that button down to the little green button--
看到那张图了吗
you see that image I have there--
视图控制器底部的那个绿色小按钮
the little green button at the bottom of the view controller
这会开启unwind segue
that is starting the unwind segue.
到模态方式present的那个
The thing that was presented modally.
你到下面这个绿按钮 然后放手
So you go down to that green thing--
and when you do to that green thing and you let go,
它会给你一系列方法 例如这里的完成
it's going to give you a list of all these methods like done right there.
这些方法都是IBAction
Okay all the methods that are IB actions
将UIStoryboardSegue作为参数
that take UI storyboard segues as arguments.
其中有些方法
Now some of those methods might be
可能在故事板中完全无关的视图控制器中
in completely unrelated view controllers off somewhere else in your storyboard because it's going to show you all of them.
Xcode知道所有这些 把它们都显示给你
Xcode knows about all of them. It shows you all of them.
如果你选择的 不在present出你的视图控制器中
If you pick one that wasn't, is not in a view controller that presented you,
unwind就不会发生 就像你什么都没做
the unwind just will not happen. It's like you did nothing.
它不会崩溃 但是什么都不会做
It's not going to crash but it's just not going to do anything.
完成按钮什么都不会做
So the done button would just do nothing.
但如果运行时 它能够找到那个方法
But if it can find, at run time if it can find that method
追溯present出你的链 它会调用那个方法
up the change of, chain of who presented you, it will call that method.
这只是unwind的一部分
Now that's only part of unwinding.
unwind的一部分是让present出你的视图控制器
Part of unwinding is letting the view controller who presented you
知道 好 我完成了
know yeah I'm done.
而这里是从公共API
And here's from public API
你从我这里获得信息
and myself [inaudible] get information out of me.
不过unwind还有另一部分 也就是为其做准备
But there's another part of it which is preparing that unwind segue.
unwind segue也需要准备
So the unwind segue has to be prepared as well.
而且准备unwind segue有时甚至比
And in fact preparing an unwind segue is even more important
准备其它segue更重要 因为只有这个机会下
sometimes than preparing other segues because it's the only chance
被present的模态视图控制器会在消失之前做点什么
that the presented modal view controller has to do anything before it goes away.
也就是准备这个unwind segue的回退
And that's to prepare that unwind segue to go back.
在demo中 我们会进一步完善Photomania
So in the demo we're going to do a photo, some more photo mania
我们会添加一张照片
and we're going to add a photo.
我们会允许从摄像头拍照
We're going to allow us to take a photo with the camera instead
而不是从Flickr取回 当这个模态视图控制器
of getting it from Flickr, and when that modal view controller
让你完成添加照片时 它需要将照片
that lets you add that photo is done, it has to put that photo
放入到数据库 然后才能unwind
in the database before it unwinds.
准备完成时segue的回退
So it prepares for the segue back when it's done
需要将照片放入数据库
by putting that photo in the database.
准备unwind segue是非常重要的
Okay so preparing for unwind segues is very important.
考虑prepareForSegue时
Now, the thing about preparing for segues is you, when you do the prepare for segue,
你需要segue的标识符
you need the segue's identifier, because you've got to know
分辨出讲的是哪个unwind segue
which unwind segue am I talking about
这对于unwind segue也很困难
and that is also difficult with unwind segues.
设置这个的唯一位置是文档大纲
The only place to set that is in the document outline.
当你通过control拖动到绿色小按钮
Okay so when you create an unwind segue by control dragging
来创建unwind segue时
down to the little green thing,
在文档大纲中 会有一行写着unwind segue
in the document outline there'll be a little line in there unwind segue,
从某个按钮
you know, from a whatever button.
你可以点这个 然后在检查器中
And you can click on that and then inspect it just
同其它segue一样 说标识符是什么
like any other segue and say the identifier is whatever.
然后在prepareForSegue中 你就有了标识符
And then in prepare for segue you'll have the identifier.
为什么这里有所不同 要隐藏起来呢
Why is that different or a little hidden?
因为unwind segue在故事板上
Well because unwind segues don't have a, you know,
没有一图 说它们要去哪
a drawing on the storyboard that says where they go
因为它们不知道要去哪
because they don't really know where they go.
这取决于谁present出它们 它们要unwind到哪
It depends on who presented them as to where they unwind to.
没有线会显示它们回去哪里
So there's no line showing them going back.
这就是需要使用文档大纲的原因
So that's why you have to use the document outline.
我会演示所有这些
So I'm going to demo all this
但愿到时候你们就都明白了
so hopefully it'll all make sense once you see it.
如何从代码上取消模态视图控制器
How about dismissing modal view controllers from code?
你想让它从屏幕上消失
So you just want to get it off the screen.
你不打算unwind 只打算让它从屏幕上消失
You're not going to unwind, you just want to get it off the screen.
顺便说下 unwind会自动让它从屏幕上消失
By the way, unwinding automatically takes it off the screen.
如果你有一个模态视图控制器 你unwind
If you have a modal view controller and you unwind,
它会自动从屏幕上消失 你不需要另外要求
it will automatically be removed from the screen, you do not have to dismiss it.
不过你也可以手动让它们消失
But you can also dismiss them manually
做法是发送消息dismissViewControllerAnimated
by sending the message dismiss view controller animated.
这个方法
This method is sent
会被发送给presenting视图控制器
to the presenting view controller,
不是被present的那个
not the presented.
而是present的那个
The presenting.
你跟视图控制器说 dismissViewControllerAnimated
You say to a view controller, dismiss view controller animated.
这意味着让任何你present的视图控制器消失
It means dismiss any view controller that you have presented.
幸运的是 如果你想在实际视图控制器中说这个
And luckily though if you want to kind of say that in the actual view controller,
还有一个很棒的方法在UIViewController中
there's a nice method in UI view controller
叫presentingViewController
called presenting view controller
这会告诉你 谁present出了你 如果有的话
which will tell you who presented you, if anyone presented you.
你可以让你自己消失
So that's a, you can dismiss yourself basically
做法是 self.presentingViewController
by saying self view controller
dismissViewControllerAnimated
dismiss animated.
根据定义 那个present出你
And since by definition that guy presented you,
这就会让你消失
when you dismiss it's going to dismiss you.
很多人不喜欢这样 因为他们认为
So just a little frowned upon because some people would argue
当一个模态视图控制器被取消时
that when a view controller, modal view controller gets canceled,
应当unwind
you want to unwind.
就算什么信息都没传回来
Even if you're not communicating anything back,
你至少要让它知道 对 我取消了
just want to let the guy know, yeah I got canceled.
如果只是取消后让自己消失
If you just cancel yourself by dismissing yourself,
那present出你的人就不能得到任何通知
then the guy who presented you doesn't get notified that you submitted yourself.
也有人说 取消了的话
But some people say yeah but if I'm cancelling I don't want
我就不需要让它知道 我什么都没做
that guy to know that I'm, I didn't do anything,
我没有添加联系人 我干嘛要让它知道
I didn't add the contact in the contact case, so I don't even want him to know.
我只需要让我自己消失即可
So I'm just going to dismiss myself.
具体采取哪种想法
So it's kind of an art of programming as to
取决于你认为怎样编程是正确的
which you believe is the right thing there.
这通常不是问题
It's usually not an issue
因为在故事板中 你都把它接了起来
because in your storyboard you're wiring it up anyway,
你总可以把取消按钮作为unwind接起来
so you could always wire it up as an unwind that cancel button instead
而不是让取消按钮进行目标动作 然后自己消失
of having the cancel button do target action and dismiss itself.
你总是可以断开任何可能设置起的目标动作
You can always just disconnect any target action that might be set up.
模态视图控制器如何出现在屏幕上呢
Okay how does the modal view controller appear on screen?
这是由这个模态过渡样式属性设置的
That's set by this modal transition style property
它位于被present的视图控制器中 这里有各种选项
in the presented view controller and it has various choices here
例如CoverVertical是从下面滑上来
like cover vertically is slide up from the bottom
demo中用的就是这个
like I showed in the demo there.
还是FlipHorizontal
There's also flip horizontal
也就是水平翻转
which will flip the new one in horizontally.
还有CrossDissolve 也就是交叉溶解淡入
There's also cross dissolve, right, which kind of fades the new one in.
PartialCurl则是卷起原来那个 展示下方的新视图
And partial curl which will curl up the current one and show the new one underneath.
这个有些奇特
That one's kind of a weird one,
想用这种卷起的人可以去看说明文档
so you'll want to check the documentation if you want to use that curl.
这里会施加一些限制
It puts some limitations on you.
卷起后 你就不能再用模态了
Once you curl it, you can't go modal again for example.
你不能present出另一个
You can't present another one.
而且卷起的那个 没有获得viewDidDisappear
Also the one that curls up, doesn't get view did disappear
因为它没有消失
because it doesn't disappear.
它只是卷起了
It kind of just curls up.
卷起后 屏幕上看不到它
You can't really see it behind the curl but it's still
但它还在屏幕上 这对编程而言很奇怪
on screen so that's a little weird programming wise.
一般而言 模态的东西会出来
Okay normally a modal thing comes up
后面那个会被完全覆盖
and the one behind it gets completely covered
这就会得到viewDidDisappear 因为视图确实消失了
so it gets view did disappear because it's view did disappear.
完全被模态那个所覆盖 但卷起不是这样
It was completely obscured by the modal one, but with the curl, not so much.
卷起要小心使用
So be careful with curl.
iPad上的所有这些呢
Now what about all this business on the iPad?
iPad上 我说了 我们将主要使用弹窗
Okay, so on iPad again mostly we're going to try and do popovers
用于这类东西 而不是模态视图控制器
for this kind of stuff instead of modal view controllers.
不过你也可以用模态视图控制器
But you can do modal view controllers
你甚至可以让模态视图控制器覆盖整个屏幕
and you can even have a modal view controller that controls, covers the whole screen.
你还可以决定它如何工作 如何覆盖
And you determine how it works, how it covers,
使用这个模态过渡样式属性
using this modal presentation style property.
这是一个不同的属性 它有一个选项便是全屏
It's a different property, and one of the options is full screen--
iPad上不推荐这样做
not recommended on the iPad.
PageSheet和FormSheet只是iPad上不同的
There's page sheet and form sheet which are just different size versions
大小规格
of the thing on the iPad.
iPad屏幕上的其它地方会变灰暗
The rest of the iPad screen will be dark gray, you know kind
就像弹窗的背景一样
of grayed out like a popover's background is,
一个会显示竖屏宽度 另一个会较小
and then it'll show up, one's portrait sized, one's a little smaller.
CurrentContext这个很有趣
And then the current context is an interesting one.
如果你有一个视图控制器和一个弹窗
If you have a popover, if you have a view controller and popover
而那个视图控制器做了模态这些
and that view controller does a modal,
那么如果是CurrentContext 这是默认值
then if its current context, which is the default,
它就会出现在弹窗中
it'll appear inside the popover.
这将是弹窗中的模态
So it'll be modal inside the popover.
懂了吗
You see what I mean?
它会同present它的视图控制器保持相同的context
So it's going to keep the same context as the view controller that presented it.
无论如何 这些的细节你们都可以自己去查
So anyway you can look all this up for details.
这两个属性在Xcode中都可以设置
It's all settable in Xcode as well, these two properties.
以上是模态视图控制器
All right so that's it for modal view controllers.
我会给出demo 你们会看到现场演示
I'm going to demo it so you'll see it all in action.
再看另一个主题 UITextField(文本框)
All right, different topic, UI text field.
我们看到过UITextView和UILabel
So we've seen UI text view and UI label.
这是文本的两极
Okay these are kind of two ends of the spectrum of text.
UILabel 不可编辑
UI label, non editable.
其中可以有带属性的文本
You know you can have attributed text in there
不过文本是静态的 你不能选它
but it's static text, can't select it or anything like that.
通常都只一行文字
Usually one line of text.
然后UITextView几乎就是一个文本编辑器
Then you've got UI text view which is almost like a text editor,
完全可编辑 所有字体和颜色 想要怎样都行
okay fully editable, all fonts and colors, everything we want.
UITextField可以说是介于两者之间
So UI text field is kind of in between those two.
它是一种UIControl 同UIButton这些一样
It's a UI control, like a UI button or something like that
你可以从这里设置目标动作
that you can set up target action from.
这些目标动作
And that target action can happen
可以在你完成文本编辑
when you're done editing the text or other
或其它文本操作后发生
things that are happening in the text and you can just,
你control拖动来做这个 你会看到各种选项
when you control drag to do it you'll see the options you have in the little
位于出现的目标动作窗口
target action window that comes up.
不过UITextField通常也只有一行文字
But it's also usually just one line of text.
不像UITextView可以有很多文本
It's not like UI text view that has [inaudible].
而且 用户通常只是提供文本
Also, the user is usually just providing the text,
不涉及到颜色 字体这些文本属性
they're not doing any colors or any of that attributed text business.
一般而言 UITextField只是纯文本
Generally UI text field is just the text and nothing but the text.
不过 它有很多特性
Having said that, it's got a lot of features
这让它非常酷 可以作为密码输入
to make it really cool for doing things like entering passwords
或是搜索框 等等
or having a search field, all those kind of things.
这是一个很强大的类
So it's a pretty powerful little class.
你可以把它看成是一个可编辑的UILabel
But it's kind of like an editable UI label if you want to think of it that way.
UITextField有一点很有趣
One thing that's interesting about a UI text field
也就是点它时 键盘会出现
of course is that when you click in it, the keyboard appears.
讲UITextView时 我并没讲键盘如何出现
Now we didn't really talk about how this keyboard appears
when we talked about UI text view,
键盘是如何出现的呢
but how does that work that the keyboard appears?
答案是 有一个方法叫becomeFirstResponder
And the answer is, there is a method called become first responder
如果你把它发送给一个文本框
that is sent, that if you send it to a text field
或是它被发送到一个文本框 键盘就会出现
or it gets sent to a text field, will cause the keyboard to appear.
你把这个方法发送给文本框
So this is a method you send to the text field.
它也可以被发送给文本视图
You can also send it to a text view.
这样做时 键盘就会出现
And when you do that, the keyboard will appear.
类似地 如果你想让键盘消失
And similarly, if you want the keyboard to go away,
你可以发送消息resignFirstResponder给文本框
you send a message to the text field, resign first responder.
第一响应器FirstResponder
But first responder means
说的是在键盘上按键后会显示在哪里
where do keyboard presses on the keyboard go?
如果你说 成为第一响应器
So if you say become first responder,
文本框会变成第一响应器
the text field becomes the first responder
键盘会出现 按键会显示到那个文本框中
and the keyboard will appear and key presses will go to that text field
resign也一样 键盘会消失
and similar to resign, it'll go away.
UITextField有委托 不像UILabel
There's a delegate for UI text field unlike UI label
这里你可以看到很多东西
and there's a lot of stuff you can see there.
demo中我会演示一个简单的例子
I'll show you a brief example in the demo.
例如 当键盘上点击回车键时
For example, when the keyboard presses the return key, when the return key is pressed
文本框被编辑 文本框的委托
and that text field is being edited the text field's delegate
会发送这条消息 textFieldShouldReturn
will send this message, text field should return.
返回应不应该发送它的目标动作
Return yes or no whether it should send its target action basically.
这里 你可以做resignFirstResponder这些事
And in there you can do things like resign first responder.
当键盘弹出后 有人点了回车 你可以让键盘消失
So when the keyboard comes up, someone hits return, you can make the keyboard go away
这通常就是用户所期望的
which is usually what users expect.
demo中我也会演示这个
So we'll see that in the demo as well.
还有其它委托方法
But there are other delegate methods,
我只是给你们举出了一个例子
I just want to give you an example of one of them there.
这些方法大概有十个
There's probably about 10 of them.
你们可以自己去说明文档查查
Check out the documentation on that.
这里是另一个 textFieldDidEndEditing
Over here's another one, text field did end editing.
resignFirstResponder完成后 这就会被发送给委托
That's sent to the delegate when it resigns first responder.
当它不再是第一响应器时 这条信息就会被发送
So when it stops being first responder, this message gets sent.
它还有一个广播站 广播每一次按键
It also has a radio station that it broadcasts on every single keystroke.
如果你想知道每次敲入文本框的是什么字符
Okay so if you want to find out every single character that's typed
你可以注册到这个广播站
in your text field you can sign up to listen to this radio station
这样你就会知道发生了什么
and you'll find out what's going on.
我说了 UITextField是受控的 你也可以设置目标动作
And like I said, UI text field is controlled so you can set up target action as well.
想知道文本框中发生了什么 你有很多方式
So there's a lot of ways to find out what's going on a text field
取决于你想要怎样的粒度
depending on the granularity that you want.
键盘 其实并没有
The keyboard, the exper- we don't,
一个属性说 给我一个键盘
there's really no property like give me the keyboard
然后我可以设置它的属性
so that I can set properties on it.
如果你想控制键盘的样子
Okay when you want to control the appearance of the keyboard,
你就需要发送消息给类 UITextField
you have to send messages to the class, UI text field
或UITextView 来弹出键盘
or UI text view that brings the keyboard up.
这些对象 这些类 都会实现这个协议
And those objects, those classes will all implement this protocol
名为UITextInputTraits
called UI text input traits.
这是一组属性 你可以在文本框或文本视图中设置
So these are the set of properties that you can set on a text field or on a text view
这不会控制文本框或文本视图的任何东西
that aren't really controlling anything about the text view or the text field,
它们控制的是弹出键盘的属性
they're controlling the properties of the keyboard that they would bring up.
这里有些属性 例如自动大写
So what are some of the properties you can have like auto capitalization.
有时在文本框中
Sometimes it's nice you have a text field,
你希望第一个键入的字母是大写
the first character you type, you want it to be capitalized.
或者每个单词的首字母大写
Or every word you type, separate word you want it
你可以设置你想要的大写方式
to be capitalized so you can set the kind of capitalization type that you have.
或许文本框中是密码
Maybe it's a password. This text field's a password
你希望键入时显示点
and so you want it to be the dots when you type them.
出于安全考虑 这里让输入字符都是点
Okay so secure text entry will make [inaudible] the dots.
回车键 键盘弹出时 它会有一个回车
The return key, when the keyboard comes up it has a little return, okay,
这个上面可以有词汇
and that can have a word on it
例如搜索 前进或是返回
like search or go, okay, or return.
你可以通过returnKeyType来控制
And you can control that with a return key type.
所有这些都是在UITextField中设置的属性
So these are all things that you set, properties you set in your UI text field
不过实际控制的是键盘
but you're really controlling the keyboard.
关于键盘还有一点
One thing about the keyboard,
它会出现在其它视图之上
it comes up on top of other views.
并覆盖它们
It covers them.
它从底部出现 覆盖它们
It comes up from the bottom, covers them.
如果文本框在最下面 这就会成问题
All right, that can be a problem if your text field's at the bottom
因为要输入的地方被盖住了
because you just covered the thing you're typing in.
一 在设计中确保UI里这个不会发生
So A, try to design your UIs so that doesn't happen.
二 如果你的视图可以滚动
But B, you can for example, if your view is scrollable,
你可以将文本框或整个视图往上滚动
maybe scroll that text field up or even just move the whole view up
这样在弹出键盘时 你就还是能看到你
so that while the keyboard's up, you can still see your text field
要键入的文本框
that you're typing into.
要知道键盘弹出
And so the way you find out the keyboard's come up
并盖住了多少
and how much it's covering
你可以收听这个广播站
is by tuning into this radio station
UIKeyboard Will或Did Show或Hide Notifications
UI keyboard will or did show or hide notification.
该通知会由你所在的窗口发送
It's a notification sent by the window you're in.
视图控制器的self.view.window
Okay, self dot view dot window for view controller.
由这个广播站得到的用户信息
And the user info that you get with this radio station
会告诉你 键盘的矩形出现在哪
will tell you the rectangles of where the keyboard appeared
你有义务将它挪开
and it's your responsibility to move it out of the way.
UIKit中唯一自动进行移动的类是
The only class in the kit, in the UI kit that will move the thing automatically
UITableViewController
for you is UI table view controller.
如果你在表格视图中有一行
So if you have a row in a table view that's
处在UITableViewController中
in a UI table view controller
而且它是可编辑文本 你将键盘弹出
and it's editable text and you bring the keyboard up,
它会自动滚动表格视图 来移动它
it'll automatically scroll the table view so move it.
这是唯一的自动做法
Okay so that's the only one that automatically does it.
其它情况下 都需要你自己来
Otherwise it's your responsibility to make,
移动被键盘挡住的东西
move anything that gets obscured by the keyboard.
其它文本框属性 你们可以自己去查
Other text field properties, you can go look those up.
它有一个很好的左右附属视图 就像annotation对话框
It has a nice left and right accessory view kind of like the annotation call out.
你甚至还可以往键盘上加一个小视图
You can even add a little view to the keyboard
使用这个inputAccessoryView
with this input accessory view.
文本框中有很多内容值得一看
There's a lot of stuff to look at in text field, I can't,
我今天没时间一一讲到
I don't have time to cover it all today
你们可以自己去看UITextField的说明文档
but you can look it all up in UI text field's documentation.
今天在demo演示前我想讲的最后一点是
All right the last thing I'm going to talk about today before the demo is
动作表单和警告
action sheet and alert.
动作表单和警告是弹出到屏幕上的东西
So action sheet and alert are things that pop up on the screen
来警告用户一些事情
to alert the user of something obviously
或是让它们作出一些选择
or to give them kind of a branching decision.
动作表单用于用户选择 警告用于警告用户
Okay action sheet for branching decisions alerts to alert them of something.
我讲它们是因为 它们有很类似的API
They have very, the reason I talk about them together, they have very similar APIs,
换言之 也就是编程接口
in other words programming interfaces.
只是用于不同的环境下
They're used in different circumstances though.
警告更多的是说 有什么事发生了
An alert is more saying something happened,
请注意 或是 我需要一点信息
pay attention, or I need a little piece of information,
请现在就给我 否则我无法继续
please give it to me right now or I can't proceed.
它有点像模态视图控制器 只是它只能
It's a little bit like a modal view controller except for that it can only,
问一个简单问题 得到一个简单答案
you know, ask a simple question and get a simple answer.
这就是警告的作用
So that's what an alert is for.
不要过度使用警告
Don't overuse alerts either.
同模态视图控制器一样 警告也不要过度使用
Just like I say don't overuse modal view controllers, don't overuse alerts.
不要任何需要信息的时候
Don't every time you need a piece of information
都弹出警告窗口找用户要
from the user just put up an alert and ask them for it.
让用户自己去点然后输入会更好
You know it's nicer for them to be able to just click on something and start typing.
你们可以看看联系人app
Take a look for example at the contacts app.
虽然联系人app会在模态视图控制器中弹出添加联系人
Even that contact app where it brought up the add contact in a modal view controller,
但在添加文本 URL或电子邮件时
when it comes to adding things like text or the, you know, URLs or emails,
都只需要点击相应位置 然后键入
you just click right there and you just type them in.
并不需要再次使用模态来获得这些信息
It doesn't go modal again on you just for that kind of information,
你们自己去看看 怎么使用才好
so check that out to see how that can be nicely used.
动作表单 可以从iPhone底部滑上来
Action sheets are, they slide up from the bottom on the iPhone,
在iPad中通常是以弹窗形式出现
they usually appear on a popover on the iPad.
它们被用于用户选择
They are for really branching decisions, so
下面 用户想做点什么
the user wants to do something next
但之前他需要告诉你
but you, they need to tell you something
让你知道下一步怎么走
so you can decide which way to go.
这就是动作表单的作用
So that's what action sheets are for.
重复一次 它们都是模态的
And again they're modal.
动作表单会让一切停止 直到用户回答了问题
They stop everything until the person answers the question of what's an action sheet.
确保这确实是你想要的UI
So make sure that's really the UI you want as opposed
你要的不是UI中的按钮 push出不同视图控制器
to just having, you know, buttons in your UI that push different view controllers.
那也是进行分支决定的方法
That's another way to do branching decisions as well.
我们会看到动作表单 这些的demo会在周三
And we'll see action sheets. I'll be demoing those on Wednesday.
这两者的API是怎样的呢
All right, what's the API for these two things look like?
很类似
Very similar.
我首先来讲动作表单
I'll start with action sheets first.
你只需alloc init
You just alloc init it.
这是动作表单的指定初始化器
Here's the designated initializer for action sheet.
它需要一个标题
You can see that it takes a title--
动作表单顶部有一个标题
the action sheet has a little title at the top.
它还有一个委托
It has a delegate.
委托会告诉你 动作表单中选的是什么
The delegate mostly will tell you what was chosen in the action sheet.
如果是在警告视图中 它会告诉你按的是哪个按钮
Or in alert view it'll tell you which button was chosen.
还有一些特殊按钮 一个是取消按钮
There are some special buttons, a cancel button,
这会取消动作表单 不做任何决定
okay which cancels the action sheet without making a decision.
毁灭性按钮
Destructive button,
动作表单中可以有一个这样的按钮
that's, you can have one button in your action sheet like that
它可以被标成红色
and that will be like in red or otherwise
告诉用户 如果你选这个
telling the user, if you choose this,
毁灭性的事情会发生
something destructive's going to happen.
例如删除这样的事情
This is like delete, or something like that.
这就是毁灭性按钮
So that's what destructive button is.
然后你可以有任意数量的标题
And then you can have as many other titles as you want.
这些是你可以选的其它分支
Those are all the other branches you can take besides the
除了毁灭性按钮 或是取消 什么都不做
destructive one or cancel, not doing anything.
你还可以通过程序添加按钮
You can also add buttons programmatically.
如果你想在alloc init中提供它们
If you don't want to provide them in the alloc init
你可以调用动作表单中的addButtonWithTitle
you can just call add button with title to add in the action sheet.
然后是显示动作表单 你可以这样做
And then it's time to display the action sheet and you'd kind
取决于你处在怎样的上下文中
of do this, depends on where, what context you're in.
在iPhone上 几乎总是用showInView
On the iPhone, you've almost always going to do show in view.
视图很多时候是self.view
A lot of times self dot view,
或者是self.view中的某个视图
or if you have a view that's inside your self dot view, you could show it from that.
在iPhone上这些都行
But it doesn't really matter on the iPhone
因为它总会从底部滑上来
because it's always going to slide up from the bottom.
无论你怎么在iPhone上呈现动作表单
No matter how you present an action sheet on an iPhone,
它总会从底部滑上来
it's always going to slide up from the bottom.
不过iPad上 它会以弹窗形式出现
But on the iPad, since it's going to appear in a popover,
使用showFromBarButtonItem这些显然会更好
it makes a lot of sense to, for example, use show from bar button item
弹窗会出现
and it'll put the popover
弹窗上的小箭头会指向那个栏按钮项目
and the little arrow on the popover will point at that bar button item.
你甚至可以用showFromRect
Or even show from rect.
你在视图中任意指定一个矩形
So you specify an arbitrary rectangle in your view
弹窗到这里 然后指向它
and it'll bring a popover up and point to that.
例如 想象你有一些文本
So for example, let's imagine you are, have some text
用户双击了一个词
and someone double clicks a word and then they want
他想定义这个词 或是复制这个词
to define the word or copy the word or something like that.
复制粘贴我可能不会用它
I probably wouldn't use it for copy and paste but
反正是对这个词做点什么
do something with that word.
这时你可能会说 showFromRect 并把这个词给矩形
And then you might say, show from rect and give the rectangle of the word.
懂我的意思吗
You see what I mean?
iBooks就是这样做的
So this is like, this is what, you know, iBooks does.
你点一个词 你说定义
You select a word and you say define,
它会弹窗 这不是动作表单 不过这是弹窗
it'll make a little popover-- that's not an action sheet but it'll make a little popover.
你可以对动作表单做相同的事
So you can do the same thing with action sheets.
在iPad上 你需要用showFromRect
Okay so on the iPad you're going to use show from rect,
showFromBarButtonItem
show from bar button item.
在iPhone上 选哪个都没关系
On the iPhone it almost doesn't matter which one you use,
它总会从底部弹出
it's going to come up from the bottom.
弄清选的是哪个按钮 这是委托方法
Finding out which button is chosen, this is the delegate method you get,
didDismissWithButtonIndex
did dismiss with button index.
这都是由按钮索引完成的
It's all done by button index.
你可以去查哪个是取消按钮 哪个是毁灭性按钮
You can look up which is the cancel button and which is the destructive button,
哪些是其它按钮
which are the other buttons.
你还可以取得按钮标题和索引 并对比选择的那个
You can also get the button title and index and compare it to the one that was chosen.
这里如果要本地化 你就需要小心一些
Be a little careful there if you're doing localization
因为你的动作表单可能会有本地化的词
because your action sheet might have localized words in it
这时你要看哪个被选了
and then you want to see which one is chosen.
确保你对比了本地化的词
Make sure you're comparing localized, the localized words, all right?
否则 如果你想更独立于本地化 你可以只使用索引
Or otherwise just use indexes if you want to kind of be more localization independent.
你也可以在程序中 取消一个动作表单
You can programmatically dismiss an action sheet.
为什么要这样做呢
And why would you ever want to do this?
弹出动作表单 让用户进行选择
Okay you put up an action sheet, a decision branch [inaudible],
为什么又要取消这个
why would you ever want to dismiss it yourself?
主要原因在于 你有可能被放入后台
Well, the main reason is, you get put in the background.
有动作表单时
So anytime you have an action sheet up
用户如果点击home键进入另一个app
and someone clicks the home button to go to another app,
这个动作表单就应当取消
you should dismiss that action sheet.
为什么这样做呢
Why would you do that?
因为当用户回到你时
Well because when the user comes back to you,
这就可能是第二天了
they'll probably be, that could be the next day.
用户可能根本记不得这个动作表单为什么弹出
They might be kind of confused why this action sheet is up.
用户不记得为什么要进行这个选择
They don't remember why they forced that branching decision.
你应当让用户回到之前那一步
So you're better to go back to the previous step for them
让其再次选择做分支决策 然后再弹出动作表单
and let them choose that branching decision again and make the action sheet come back up.
怎么知道你进入了后台呢
So how do you find out you entered the background?
这里有个很棒的广播站
There's this nice radio station,
UIApplicationDidEnterBackgroundNotification
UI application did enter background notification.
你只需要收听这个
You just listen to that, boom,
你就知道自己是否被丢到了后台
you'll find out you were put in the background.
如果被丢到后台 取消动作表单
Just dismiss the action sheet, and you know how to do this
使用block 这很简单
with blocks so it's really really easy.
一行代码 弹出动作表单后
One liner when you put up the action sheet
一行代码 当广播站说到了后台后
to put a one liner in there that when it gets to this radio station,
动作表单就会被取消
it just dismisses it.
弹窗还有一些特殊考虑
There's special popover considerations.
这里弹窗动作表单也有相同的问题
We have the same problem here with popover action sheets
同Photomania中一样
that we had when we did PhotoMania
我们点URL时会得到越来越多的弹窗
where we kept pressing a URL and we got more and more and more of them.
这里也是一样
Okay same thing here.
在动作表单弹出时要小心 不要再弹出
You have to be careful if your action sheet's already up, don't put it up again.
再看警告视图
Alert view.
警告视图可以有多个按钮 像左边这样
Alert view can have multiple buttons like the one on the left.
也可以有文本框 像右边这样
It can also have a little text field in it like the one on the right
这很有趣
which is kind of fun.
它的API同动作表单完全一样
And its API looks exactly like action sheet.
你可以从程序添加按钮
You can add buttons programmatically.
显示它只需要一个方法show
Showing it is always just the one method show
因为警告总会弹出到屏幕中央
because alerts always come up in the middle of the screen.
我想我说过 只有表格视图控制器可以移开
I think I said only table view controllers will move out of the way.
警告也可以移开
Alerts will also move out of the way.
如果由于有文本框而弹出键盘
If you bring up a keyboard because there's a text field in your alert,
警告会往上移
the alert will move up.
显示 在iPad和iPhone上 都只需要show
So anyway, show. On either iPad or iPhone, you just do show.
这是在警告中获得文本框的方式
Here's how you get a text field in your alert.
你只需要说alert.alertViewStyle =
You just say alert dot alertviewstyle equals
这其中一种有文本的样式
one of these styles that has text:
SecureText PlainText LoginAndPassword
secure text, plain text, login and password.
然后你得到文本框
And then you get the text field
你能从中获得文本
so you can get the text out of them
通过alertView textFieldAtIndex
by alert view text field add index.
索引0 这是只有一个文本框的情况
Okay, index zero if there's only one text field.
索引0和1 例如有帐号和密码的情况
Index zero and one if there's login and password for example.
这就是得到文本框的方式
So that's how you can get text field.
下面是demo时间 所有这些我都会在demo中演示
All right, time for the demo so I'm going to show all of these things in the demo.
我说了 我们会完善Photomania
And like I said, what we're going to do is we're going to enhance PhotoMania
让用户能够通过摄像头来拍照
so that it can, so the user can take photos with their camera.
今天我们不打算讲到摄像头那部分
Now we're not actually going to get to the camera part today,
不过其它我们都会演示
but we're going to do all the rest of it.
最重要的是 我们将用到modal segue
Most importantly we're going to do that modal segue
和unwind segue
and unwind segue
让这个找用户要照片的视图控制器出现
to put this view controller up that's going to ask for the photo.
这将是一个视图控制器
Okay it's going to be a view controller.
它的作用就是让用户使用摄像头拍照
Its only job is to let the user take a picture with the camera,
给照片一个标题和一个副标题 找到其位置
give it a title and subtitle, find out their location.
这里我还会回头给出Core Location的demo
Okay I'm going to go back and show you a core location demo here
因为之前我没演示过
because I never showed you that before.
然后 我将能创建一张照片
And then now I can create a photo
因为这里我有了所有信息 标题 子标题 图像
because I've got all the pieces-- title, subtitle, image,
我要设置一个缩略图 然后是位置
I'll make a thumbnail, and then the location.
我可以在数据库中创建一张照片
Now I can make a photo in the database.
大家都理解我们要做什么了吗
Okay everyone understand what we're going to do?
好 下面来演示
Okay, let's dive right in here.
先看看后面的内容 因为后面我们不会回到幻灯片了
I'm going, let's show coming up because I'm not going to go back to the slides.
后面我会继续这个demo 加入摄像头部分
I'll continue this demo by doing the actual camera part
然后我还会谈到Core Motion
and then I'm also going to talk about core motion
也就是加速计 陀螺仪这些
which is accelerometer, gyro, all that stuff,
这是周三的内容 我们有另外一个demo
on Wednesday, okay with another demo.
周五的辅导课是Sprite Kit
Friday's section is sprite kit
这是iOS7的新工具包 用于2.5D游戏
which is a new iOS 7 kit for doing 2.5D games.
看起来是3D
Okay games that look 3D
但实际上是由2D图像做成
but they're really made out of 2D images.
然后下一周放假
And then next week we have off and then
回来以后 我们还有各式主题
when we come back we'll have more miscellaneous topics.
好 Photomania 在哪
Okay so PhotoMania, where is it?
在上课之前 我给Photomania加了一个东西
Okay so just before class I added one thing to PhotoMania
我打算展示我所加的代码
and I'm going to show you the code I added.
我为用户加了一个拍照者到数据库
What I did was I added a photographer to my database for the user.
这是一个拍照者 也就是使用我们设备的用户
Okay this is the photographer, the user, who's using my device.
因为这里我将添加这位用户所拍的照片
That's because I'm going to add photos and he's going to,
her or she, is going to be the photographer.
怎么做到呢
So how did I do that?
我将两个方法加到了我的Photographer category
I added these two methods to my photographer category here,
userInManagedObjectContext
user in managed object context.
这给了我一个唯一的拍照者 用于用户
That gives me a photographer for the user, unique photographer.
然后isUser则是检验 这个拍照者是不是用户
And then is user which just tells me whether a particular photographer is the user.
这个的实现我做得很简单
And the implementation of these, I kind of went cheapo,
或许还有更好的做法
there'll probably be much better ways to do this,
我只是创建了一个拍照者 名为 My Photos
but I just created a photographer with the name my photos,
我还在前面加了个空格 这样它就会排在前面
and I put a spacebar at the beginning so it would sort at the beginning.
更好的做法
But really the way to do this would be
其实是添加另一个属性到拍照者 也就是"是用户"
to add another attribute to your photographer which is, is the user.
然后排序再把这个排到第一位 然后再按名字排
And then when you sort, you would sort by that first, and then secondarily by the name.
这样这个名字就不需要这么特殊
And that would make it so that this name wouldn't have
因为我们将使用属性来设置
to be unique because it would be the, you know, that attribute set.
这里 我检查了用户是不是self
And then here I'm just checking to see if the user is self.
我在这里只加了一行
The only other line of code I added
也就是 在数据库context可用时 我总会在app委托中
to this was I always create this magic user in app delegate
创建这个特殊的用户
when the database context becomes available.
就是这样了
That's it.
大家都明白之前我做的吗
Everyone understand what I did so far?
所有我都展示过
I've shown you everything.
我们看看这是怎样的
So let's look what this looks like.
运行Photomania 可以看到这里
So here I'm running PhotoMania and you can see right here
最开始我就有一个拍照者 My Photos 我可以点它
at the beginning I have a photographer, my photos, and I can click on it.
它会显示我的所有照片
I'll show all my photos.
现在一张都没有 因为摄像头这些我们还没用到
I don't have any yet because we haven't hooked up this whole camera business.
不过在这个UI中 我会考虑我的照片
But what I'm going to do in this UI is when I'm looking
并在这上面加一个小按钮
at my photos, I'm going to add a little button up here,
形如相机 它会通过模态present出一个视图控制器
looks like a camera, and it's going to modally present a view controller
这就让我能够拍照 并存入数据库中
that lets me take a picture and put it in the database.
好 我们将把它加到这里
Good. All right so that's what we're going to do, we're just going to add this here.
看_Night Flyer_时 我们不希望
Now, that camera, we don't want that camera button here
相机按钮出现在这里
when we're looking at night flyer.
我们显然不能添加_Night Flyer_的照片
Okay we don't want that night flyer to be able to add one,
我们只能对My Photos做这件事
so we're only going to do it when it's my photos.
这个要怎么做呢
All right, so how are we going to do that?
看我们的视图
Let's go look at our view.
我们打算在iPhone上来做
We're going to do this on the iPhone.
周三我们可能不会再在iPad上做
Probably not going to get around to doing it on the iPad
我们将只针对iPhone
on Wednesday, we'll just do it iPhone only.
这是我的拍照者列表
Here is my list of photographers.
这是那个地图视图 带有特定拍照者的照片
Here is that map view with the photos by a given photographers.
这里是我希望有那个按钮的位置
Here's where I want to have that little map button.
因此 我只需要到这下面 抓取一个栏按钮项目
So I'm just going to go down here and grab a bar button item.
它在这里
Here's one right here.
放到这里
Put it here.
我可以在这里写相机 拍照或别的什么
I could say the word camera or take photo or something here,
不过这里可以用一个内建的相机按钮
but it actually turns out there's a nice built-in one for camera.
内建栏按钮项目
Whoo, built in bar button item.
看起来很棒
Looks good.
重复一次 我只打算在拍照者是用户本人时
So again I only want to have this camera appear when I'm showing the photographer
才显示这个按钮
who is the user.
我要在PhotosByPhotographerMapViewController中
So I'm going to put a little bit of code in my photos
加入一段用于这个的代码
by photographer map view controller which is the code for that thing,
只在那种情形下显示按钮
to only show that button in that circumstance.
首先 我要创建一个outlet到它
So first of all I'm going to create a little outlet to it.
这里腾出一些空间来显示这些
Trying to make it more space here as I show these.
这里是这个
Okay so here is this guy right here
我要到.m文件
and I'm going to go to the dot m.
这是我的PhotosByPhotographerMapViewController
So here's my photos by photographer with map view controller.
这个就在这里
That's this. That's where this is.
我要control拖动
So I'm going to control drag
从这个小按钮 为它创建一个outlet
from this little button right here to make a outlet for it.
命名为addPhotoBarButtonItem
I'm going to call it the add photo bar button item.
这样我就得到了addPhotoBarButtonItem
So I've got my add photo bar button item.
然后我还要加一点代码
And now I'm just going to put a little bit of code
只在拍照者是用户时才把按钮放到这里
that only puts that here if my current photographer--
这是我为这些设定拍照者的地方
here's where I set my photographer for this thing-- is the user.
这里我将有一个方法 self
So I'm going to have a little method here. I'm going to call it self
updateAddPhotoBarButtonItem
update, add photo, bar button item.
我需要这个更新函数
And I'm just going to have a little-- this update this thing.
我们这里需要Photographer+Create
We need photographer create for that
因为这就是我们要加入的地方
because that's where that thing we just added.
这是我刚才快速键入的
All right so here's what I just typed in right here really fast
你们可以离线去看
and you can look at this offline.
这里没有什么新东西 我就不讲了
There's nothing really new to teach you here so I'm not going to go through it.
只需要知道 它会更新这里这个导航项目的
But suffice it to say it's really updating the right bar button items
正确的栏按钮项目 来决定有没有这个
of this navigation item right here to have this or not.
我们来看看
So let's go take a look.
来到这里 它有这个
Okay so we go here, it's got this.
回到这里 它没有
Go back here, doesn't have it.
这很好
See? Okay so that's good.
下面我们需要 按这个按钮时
So now we need to make it so when we press this
程序就会modal segue到新UI
we do this modal segue to a new UI.
我们来做这个 回到iPhone故事板来腾空间
So let's go do that, back to our iPhone storyboard to make space.
让我们把这个做成新UI来做这个
All right so let's make this new UI that we want to do that,
我要创建一个新视图控制器 拖出来
so I'm going to create a new view controller here, drag this out.
这是我的新视图控制器
Here's my new view controller.
将它很好地对齐到这里
Okay, and we'll line it up there nicely.
这个视图控制器中有些什么呢
And what is this view controller going to have in it?
我们看看 我要从这里拖出很多好东西
Well, let's see, I'm going to drag a whole bunch of nice stuff out here.
它需要一个取消按钮 这里我们放个取消
It wants a cancel button, so let's do a cancel.
这时我会决定 我其实不想添加
That's if I decide eh, I don't really want to add one after all.
它还需要一个完成按钮
It wants a done button.
来执行完成操作
So if we're going to do a done,
它还需要一个拍照按钮
it probably wants a take photo button, okay,
点它会弹出拍照用户界面
that we'll click that will cause us to bring up the camera taking user interface.
这个放到上面这里
I will put these somewhere here, put that up there.
这个对齐地放到这里
Let's put this one lined up over there.
这个放到别处
Put this somewhere.
我需要一个图像视图 一个UIImageView
We need a view, I want to have an image view, a UI image view
为我显示我刚拍的照片
that shows me what I just took with the camera.
把这个拖出来 放到这里
So let's drag that out, put that here let's say.
或许是这样 拉成一个正方形
Maybe, I don't know, something like let's make it square.
这就是我的正方形
There, that's my square one.
把拍照拉下一些
Put take photo down here.
然后 对于标题和副标题再放一些文本框
Okay, and then I'm going to have some text fields for the title and subtitle.
把它们拖出来
So let's drag those out.
这是文本框 我们第一次用它
So here's text field, first time we've used that.
像这样 这就有了一个
But here we go. There's one there.
拉宽一些 像这样
Let's make it a little wider, like that.
为标题和副标题粘贴复制
Let's copy and paste for title and subtitle.
为这些东西加个标签
Let's get a label for each of these things.
这是副标题标签 复制粘贴 这是标题标签
There's the subtitle label and let's copy and paste the new title label.
然后把这些对齐
And then let's line these things up.
像这样
Something like that.
我们要对齐基线
We'll line up the baselines probably of our--
把这个挪开 这里对齐基线
let's get that out of the way-- line up the baselines here.
中间可能好了
Center's probably just as good.
就这样吧 这就标题和副标题
So anyway, so there's our title, there's our subtitle.
然后我们创建一个UIViewController的自定义子类
And now let's create a custom UI view controller subclass
这样我们就能把所有这些东西关联起来
so we can wire all this business up to something.
我们可以到这里点新文件
So we can go here, new, file.
创建一个新的
And we're creating a new one.
这将是一个常规的UIViewController
This is going to be a normal UI view controller.
让我们把它称作AddPhotoViewController
It's going to call, let's call it add photo view controller
这就是它的作用
because that's what it does, right?
它会添加一张照片到数据库 这是一个很好的名字
It adds a photo to the database so that's a good name for it.
把这同其它所有控制器放一起
We'll put it where all the rest of our controllers are.
这里
There it is.
这是我们的init
Okay, this is our init, we don't need any
这一大堆样板内容都不需要
of this boilerplate that it puts in here.
删掉这些
Get rid of that.
让我们来设置它的ID
Let's go ahead and set our identity of this thing
设为这个新的AddPhotoViewController
to be this new add photo view controller.
让我们关联一些outlet 来指向这其中一些东西
Let's wire up some outlets to point to some of these things.
我们需要outlet到这两个文本框 让我们来做这个
All right so, we need an outlet to both of these text fields, so let's do that.
这是我们的标题文本框 和这个关联起来
This is our title text field and we'll wire this one up.
这是我们的副标题文本框
This is our subtitle text field.
我们再点亮取消按钮
And let's light the cancel button.
关联起这个
Let's wire that up.
取消 完成
Cancel. Done.
我们再来关联拍照片按钮
Let's wire up the take photo.
拍照片
Take photo.
完成 好
Done. Okay.
我不喜欢这样 我们这样
Now you know I don't like those like that so we'll do that.
我们再把这个图像视图关联起来
Let's also wire up this image view right here.
我还要做一件事 碰到这样的图像视图时
Okay I'm also going to do something that I did in image view controller
我总喜欢在图像视图控制器中做这件事 也就是
which I always like to do when I have an image view like that, which is I'm going
设置一个非原子的 强的UIImage *image属性
to have a non atomic strong UI image star image.
这里有一个属性叫image
Okay so I'm going to have a property called image
不过我会将它存在图像视图中
but I'm going to store it in the image view.
我们对视图控制器做过相同的事
Same exact thing we did for view controller.
这里我们将加入setImage
So here I'm just going to have set image.
它会在图像视图控制器中进行设置
Okay and it's just going to set in the image view controller
并返回图像视图控制器
and return the image view controller.
这样做是因为我需要
And the reason I'm doing this is because I'm going to need
在以后图像被设置时做些事情
to do some things when the image is set in the future.
因此 我需要预先把这个准备好
So I'm just kind of getting it ahead of myself and getting it ready for that.
大家都理解我刚做的吗
Everyone understand what I'm doing there though?
好 下面把这个放到屏幕上
Okay, so let's go ahead and put this on screen briefly
通过创建一个modal segue 从这里到这里
by creating a modal segue from here to here.
我还想简单展示一下这些文本框
And I just want to show you a little bit about these text fields.
我要让这个像这样
So I'm just going to have this guy right here go like this,
这里不选push 而选modal
and instead of push I'm going to do modal.
这就会让这个用modal方式显示在屏幕上
So that's going to put this thing on screen modally.
这是一个modal segue
This is a modal segue right here.
这里我们可以称它为Add Photo Segue
This for example, we could call it the add photo segue.
检查标识符或许甚至可以掠过
I'll probably skip even checking that identifier.
无论如何 我们试运行一下
But anyway, let's go ahead and run
把这个放到屏幕上 展示一些文本框的内容
so we can get this thing on screen and I can show you something about the text field.
这里是我们的相机
So here we go, here's our camera.
点它 它会用modal方式显示在屏幕上
And when I click this, it comes up on screen modally.
modal一定要有取消的办法
Now one thing about modal, you better have a way to get rid of it.
这个我们还没关联
And we haven't wired any of this up.
我的app这就完了
This is, my app is done now.
我无法回退
I can't get back.
我需要要么unwind 要么取消
So I have to either unwind or I have to cancel myself.
但我现在还没做这些
But we're not doing that right now,
我现在只想看看这些文本框
what I'm doing now is I want to look at these text fields.
我点标题 然后就可以开始输入标题
So if I click here title, okay, and I could type, start typing
好 这就是我想要的标题了
in a title here, and I'm like okay that's where I want the title to be.
但点这个没反应
Oh, I can't get, I can't get rid of this.
键盘无法消失
There's no way to get rid of this keyboard.
点别处都没用
Okay there's nowhere I can click,
我什么都做不了 这个一直都在
there's nothing I can do, this thing is up.
而且我的照片在它下面 照片也看不见
And my photo is underneath it, so I can't see my photo.
这太糟糕了
Okay this is awful.
在点return时 我需要能够消掉这个键盘
So I really want to be able to dismiss this keyboard when I hit return here.
我们可以使用UITextFieldDelegate来做这个
So we can do that using the UI text field's delegate.
我们来做这个
So let's go ahead and do that.
我们到这里来
Okay we're going to go here
我要做点有趣的事 我从没这样做过
and I'm going to do something a little interesting we haven't done before
也就是 我要在故事板中关联一个委托
which is I'm going to wire up a delegate in the storyboard.
这一般是在代码中做的事
Normally we would do this in code.
例如文本框的setter被调用时
Like when the setter for that text field was called we'd say
我们说textField.delegate = self
self, you know, we'd say text field dot delegate equals self.
但这里 我直接control拖动
But here I'm going to do it by control dragging
从文本框到我的视图控制器
from the text field down to my view controller.
这时 我就可以设置它的委托了 看到了吧
And when I do you'll see that I can set its delegate.
我将文本框的委托设置为我的视图控制器
So I'm setting the text field's delegate to be my view controller.
另一个我也来设置
I'll set the other one too.
这两个 右键点击你都能看到
So both of these guys, if you right click on them you'll see
它们的委托是Add Photo View Controller
that their delegate is my add photo view controller.
在AddPhotoViewController中
Now I still have to, in my add photo view controller right
这里 我还需要说
here, I still have to say oh yes,
我是一个UITextFieldDelegate
I'm a UI text field delegate.
还是那句话 所有这些方法都是可选的
All right now again, all these methods are optional
没有这些关系也不大
so it really wouldn't be that big a deal if I didn't
不过 为了程序的恰当 我会这样做
but still, just to be proper, I should do that.
现在 我可以实现这其中一些
And I, now I can implement some of these ones.
例如这里有一个叫
Like a good one here would be shou- what's it called?
textFieldShouldReturn
Text field should return.
textField打头的还有一些
So here's some of the text field ones. These ones [inaudible].
我们要的是textFieldShouldReturn
So let's do text field should return.
如果文本框问我 我是否该return
And so if the text field asks me, should I return?
我会说 是 你该return
I'm going to say yes, you should return.
也就是说 如果有目标动作在return时发生 做就是了
Meaning if you have target action that fires when you return, go ahead and do it.
不过我还要说 文本框先生 请消掉第一响应器
But I'm also going to say, Mr. Text Field, please resign first responder.
换言之 停止使用键盘
In other words, stop using the keyboard.
加入这些代码 然后运行
So just by putting this in here, now when we run
转到这个界面 点这里
and bring this baby back up and we click here
开始输入 点return 文本被留在了这里
and we start typing and we hit return, it leaves the text in there,
虽然这里有一些拼写错误校正
even does its little fixing the misspellings.
键盘消失了
And the keyboard goes away.
我可以让它弹出来 然后再让它消失
And I can bring this one back and make this one go away.
这个UI就好很多了 特别是让键盘能够消失
So it's a much nicer UI to be able to make that keyboard go away especially
键盘下如果有东西 你就不需要滚动到上面来
if you have something underneath the keyboard and you don't scroll it up.
我展示这个
So I just wanted to show you that just
只是想让你们知道 一
to show you how we can A,
如何在故事板中设置文本框委托
set the text delegate in the storyboard,
二 如何使用委托来做一些有价值的事
and B, how we could use a delegate method to do something valuable.
以上就是关于文本框我要演示的东西
So that's all I'm going to show you for text field.
剩下的内容你们应该可以自己去看
I think you can figure out the rest on your own.
下面我们再回到segue
All right so now let's get back to the segueing okay?
我们有这个 它segue到这里
So we have this guy right here and it segues to here.
我们已经设置了这个modal segue
So we already set up this modal segue,
我们没有准备它 也不能从它unwind
but we don't actually prepare it nor can we unwind from it.
这两个视图控制器之间的整个关系还没有完成
So we really haven't finished with the whole relationship
between these two view controllers.
我们首先看看这个模态视图控制器的公共API
So let's first look at the public API of this modal view controller to kind
来理解它是如何通信的
of understand how it's going to communicate.
我们来看看AddPhotoViewController的公共API
So I'm going to look at the public API of add photo view controller
它有两个东西
and it really has two things.
它有一个输入
It has an input
也就是photographerTakingPhoto(拍照的拍照者)
which is the photographer who is taking the photo.
这里我们或许总是会传入用户 这个特殊拍照者
Now hopefully we always pass in the user, right, that special photographer.
不过这个AddPhotoViewController可以更通用一些
But this add photo view controller can be more generic
它可以说 给我一个拍照者
about it and just say, hey give me a photographer,
我要拍张照 然后为这个拍照者将其添加到数据库
I'll take a photo and add it to the database for that photographer.
不过我们会有我们的地图
But we're going to have our map,
PhotosByPhotographerMapViewController
photos by photographer map view controller.
如果是用户 而且相机按钮被点
If it's the user and that camera button gets pressed,
我们就会传入用户的那个
we're going to pass in the user's one.
这是入
So that's the in.
这里导入Photographer
So that's import photographer.
我们还需要导入Photo
And we're also going to import photo while I'm here
因为这个视图控制器还有一个输出 也就是
because this thing, this view controller also has an output which is
非原子 强
nonatomic strong
添加到数据库的照片
the photo that was added to the database.
应该是Photo
Oops, photo.
这是一个AddPhotoViewController
Okay so this is an add photo view controller.
它为给定拍照者添加一张照片
It adds a photo for that given photographer
完成这个后 这就会被设为它添加的照片
and when it's done doing that, this will be set to the photo it added.
segue到它的人 unwind回来后就能看到
So anyone who segues to it, when they unwind back, they can look
添加的是什么照片
and see what was the photo that was added?
理解这里我们做的是什么吗
That make sense what we're doing there?
我们需要从入和出两方面来实现这个API
So we have to implement this API both on the way in and on the way out.
首先看入
So let's talk about on the way in first
因为这是你们习惯的常规segue
because that's normal segueing that you're used to.
在PhotosByPhotographerMapViewController中来做
We're just going to do this in our photos by photographer map view controller
我们只需要准备这个segue
and all we're going to do is prepare that segue.
这之前
Before we do that let's go ahead
我们先导入AddPhotoViewController
and import our add photo view controller
因为我们要用它 我们要准备它
because we're going to use it. We're going to prepare it.
让我们这样做
And so let's do that.
这是prepareForSegue
And here's prepare for segue.
这是一个很常规的segue 和其它segue一样
This is a normal segue just like any other segue
我要准备它
and I'm just going to prepare it.
让我们说 如果sender…
Let's say if the sender--
不对 如果segue的目标视图控制器
no if the segue's destination view controller is kind
是AddPhotoViewController这一类
of class, add photo view controller,
那么AddPhotoViewController *apvc
then add photo view controller-- add photo view controller--
= (AddPh… 你们不要沿用我这种糟糕的风格
equals add ph- yeah you guys should not be using my bad style
我这里只是出于demo方便
here but that's demo naming right there.
segue.destinationViewController
Segue dot destination view controller.
这里我有了要segue到的视图控制器
Okay so now I have the view controller I'm segueing to here
在这个modal segue中
in this modal segue so I'm going
我要设置它的photographerTakingPhoto
to set its photographer that's taking the photo
= self.photographer
equal to self dot photographer.
这将总是用户 因为只有是用户时
Now this is always going to be the user because the only time
那个相机按钮才会出现在右上角
that little camera button is there is when it's the user.
不过这里出于双保险考虑 我可以检查是不是用户
But to be double safe here, maybe I would want to check and see is user, right,
[inaudible] photographer is user.
这里我就不检查了 毕竟是demo
But I'm not going to be double safe because it's demo.
这是这个segue
So there, that's that segue.
如果sender是annotation 我还要处理这个segue
I'm still going to do this segue if the sender is an annotation.
换言之 有人点了大头针
In other words, someone clicks on the pin, [inaudible] do that one too.
这里或许我应该放到else里面
I could probably put an else in here if I wanted to.
或者else if
Even else if.
像这样
Something like that.
因为这里不是一种情况 就是另一种
Okay because obviously it's going to be one or the other.
或许我还应该检查segue标识符 确保是Add Photo
I also probably could've checked my segues identifier here to make sure it's add photo.
想的话 我可以那样做
I can do that if I want to.
无论如何 但愿这部分segue你们完全理解了
But anyway, hopefully this side of this segue you totally understand, right?
常规segue 我们只是采用了modal方式
Okay, normal segueing, we're just doing it modally rather than not.
现在往前解决了
Okay, so now we've got to it.
下面才是麻烦的部分 即unwind
Now the hard part, unwinding.
我们希望在完成工作时听到它的回复
So now we want to hear about it when the thing is done.
我说过 这个完成时
And I told you that that's done
通过实现一个特殊的IBAction方法
by implementing a special IB action, okay, method,
叫什么都行 它unwind时会发生什么呢
and we can call it anything we want. And what is going to happen when it's unwinding?
一张照片会被添加
Well a photo's going to be added.
或许我应该把这个方法叫作addedPhoto
So maybe I'll call this method added photo.
因为这就是它的作用
Because that's what it does.
真正关键的是 参数是一个UIStoryboardSegue
And the real key is that the argument is a UI storyboard segue.
这是unwind时需要调用的方法
So this method is the method that's going to get called when we unwind, all right?
加入这个之后 Xcode就知道了
Now the very adding of this has caused Xcode to know about it,
当我们回到故事板control拖动
so that if we go back to our storyboard and wind u-
来关联 来unwind 它就会自动
you know control drag to hook up and unwind, it's going to know about it.
让我们来做这个
So let's go do that.
我们回到了这里
We're back in our thing here.
取消
Cancel.
我们简单谈下取消
Let's talk about cancel briefly.
这里我打算在点取消时
I'm going to make the executive decision that cancel,
仅仅消掉而不unwind
it's just going to dismiss, it's not going to unwind.
我这里已经有了一个取消方法
All right? And I already have a cancel method right here.
我已经将它同目标动作关联了起来
I already wired it up for target action.
怎么做到呢
So how do I do that?
self.presentingViewController
Self dot presenting view controller presenting
dismiss… YES
dismiss, yes.
该完成处理器在视图控制器完全被消掉时就会被调用
And this completion handler is called once the view controller is fully dismissed.
也就是说 在其viewDidDisappear被调用之后
In other words, after its view did disappear is called.
那时 我们什么都不需要做
We don't need to do anything at that time.
有些人认为 这比它实际更神奇
Some people think this, this is more magic than it is.
这是一个很简单的方式 在这个东西消失后
It's really just a simple way to, after this thing is gone,
做点什么来收尾
do something to clean up or something.
不过 我们不需要做这个
But we're no, we don't need to do that.
无论如何 取消就是这样了
So anyways, so that's it. So that cancel.
我们现在可以运行一下
So in fact if we run right now
选My Photos再到这里 取消就能奏效了
and we bring our photos and we go up here, cancel will work you see?
视图被消掉了
It just dismisses it.
它没有unwind 没有调用addedPhoto
And it doesn't unwind, it doesn't call that added photo.
取消只是让其消失
It just cancels it, gone.
完成 这个是我们要unwind的
Now done, this is the one we want to unwind.
我们希望它创建这张照片 然后unwind回来
We want it to create this photo and then unwind back
到这个地图视图控制器 并调用addedPhoto
to this map view controller right here and call added photo.
addedPhoto被调用时 我们要做什么
Okay what's, what are we going to do when added photo is called?
我们来看看
Well, let's see.
我们来做一些事情
Let's do a couple of things.
一 让我们确保这个的来源
One, let's make sure that the source
是一个AddPhotoViewController
of this is an add photo view controller,
它显然应该是
which it should be
因为我们只知道对这个进行unwind
because it's the only thing we know how to unwind for.
而且 还有谁能调用addedPhoto呢
And also because who else would call added photo?
无论如何 我们会检查它
But we'll check it anyway.
然后 我要复制粘贴这个
And then we're going to do, I'm going to copy and paste this
这就不需要重新键入了
so I don't have to type all that again.
不过这里要变
Okay now I'm just going to change,
这是源视图控制器
but this is the source view controller instead
而不是目标视图控制器
of the destination view controller.
我有了我的apvc
So I've got my APVC.
然后我说 添加的照片是什么
Now I'm going to say, okay well what was the photo that was added?
是apvc的addedPhoto
Well it's the APVCs added photo.
这是它公共API的一部分 公共API的出那部分
That's part of its public API, the out of its public API.
我把这抓出来 我打算说
So I'm grabbing that out, and now I'm going to say
如果我们加了一张照片 那么我想做什么呢
if we added a photo, then what might I want to do?
我在显示PhotosByPhotographer
I'm the map view-- I'm showing photos by a photographer
因此我可以这样
so I probably want to do, for example,
mapView addAnnotation 这张addedPhoto
map view, add annotation this added photo.
换言之 将这张照片加到我的地图
In other words, add this photo to my map.
我还可以说 self.mapView 显示那个annotation
I might also want to say self dot map view show that annotation.
放大到那个拍照所在的位置
Zoom in to that part of the world where the photo was taken.
我或许还可以说
I might want to say, I probably want to say
photosByPhotographer = nil
photos by photography equals nil
并重新计算这个
and have that recalculate
因为我为这个拍照者添加了一张新照片
because I've added a new photo for this photographer.
这样下次有人问我这个 它就能够工作
So the next time someone asks me about that it'll work.
否则 出于教学目的 我可以查看日志
Otherwise, for instructional purposes here, I'm going to log
这里我可以说
and say
AddPhotoViewController没有…
add photo view controller, did not--
我甚至可以说 出乎意料地没有添加照片
or I'll even say-- unexpectedly did not add a photo.
因为unwind时 应该会添加一张照片
Okay because if I'm getting unwound to, it should have added a photo.
如果这里是nil 那就肯定出错了
Okay so if this is nil, then something's wrong.
我们会看到这种情况发生
So but we're going to see that happen because we're going
我们会尝试没添加照片到数据库的情况
to try this without adding the, without the photo being added
看看那时会发生什么
to the database and see what happens here.
大家都理解这些对吧
So everyone understands what happen- what's going on here right?
我们正unwind回这个
We're unwinding back to this guy.
这个正在接收unwind
This guy is receiving the unwind
并对添加的照片做些什么
and doing something with the photo that was added with the add photo.
好 让我们把这些关联起来
All right so now let's go ahead and wire that up.
我说了 我们会选择这里导致unwind的UI
So as I said, we're going to pick whatever UI in here is going to cause the unwind,
也就是完成按钮
which is the done button.
我要control拖动到这个绿色按钮
I'm going to control drag to this green button.
释放后 看看会发生什么
And when I let go, watch what happens.
看到addedPhoto出现在列表中了吗
You see how added photo is in the list?
拥有UIStoryboardSegue作为参数的任何IBAction
And every single IB action that had a UI storyboard segue as an argument
都会被列在这里
would be listed here.
不过这里只有addedPhoto 这正是我们要的
But added photo, obviously only one, it's the one we want,
我要点这个
so I'm going to click that.
现在 我创建了unwind 它会unwind回这个
So now I've created an unwind that will unwind back to this guy.
我说过 这只能在文档大纲中看到
And I told you that the only place you can really see this is in the document outline.
这里
You can see it right here.
看到了吗 unwind segue从完成到退出
See? Unwind segue from done to exit.
这是一个常规的segue
And I can, this is a normal segue
因此我可以设置它的标识符
so I could set its identifier for example to something
例如Do Add Photo这之类
like do add photo or something like that
因为该unwind segue的作用就是添加照片
because that's what this unwind segue does. It does the add photo.
这就是完成的作用
It's the done basically.
不过这个我甚至不需要做
Okay but I wouldn't even need to do that.
最后我还是需要做这个 不过目前还不用
So let's go-- well I will need to do it eventually-- but for this so far I didn't.
下面我运行一下 看会发生什么
So let's go ahead and see what happens here when we run this.
我打算到这里 再到这里
Okay so I'm going to go here, I'm going to go here,
这次点完成 看它unwind
and I'm going to hit done this time and we'll watch it unwind.
它unwind了
Okay it unwound, right?
窗口被消掉
It dis- dismissed it.
看看下面这里的控制台信息
And look down in my console down here.
AddPhotoViewController出乎意料地没有添加照片
Add photo view unexpectedly did not add a photo
这正是我们所期望的
which is exactly what we'd expect, right?
它unwind到了这里 做了这个 但没有添加照片
It unwound over to here, did this, but it never added the photo
因为UI中我没有获得所有信息
because I never take all the information here that's in my UI
例如标题 副标题 照片
like the title, the subtitle, the photo--
我没有把这些添加到照片中 并添加到数据库
I never put them into a photo and added it to the database.
它说得没错
So it's right.
这里的汇报很正确 因为确实没有添加照片
This thing is properly reporting here that it did not add a photo.
我们来处理这个 怎么做呢
So let's do that. How do we do that?
这就是prepareForSegue对unwind非常重要的地方
This is where prepare for segue is so important for unwinds.
因为prepareForSegue…
Because prepare for segue--
因为这个unwind segue发生在这个视图控制器中
since this unwind segue happens in this view controller, okay--
unwind到这里 所以这个需要准备
unwinds over to there, this guy gets to prepare.
这个在做准备时 需要创建照片
And what this guy wants to do when he prepares is create that photo.
理解吗
Make sense?
这里要创建照片 我们只需要prepareForSegue
So all we got to do to make that photo is implement prepare
这里 在添加视图控制器中
for segue here in this add view controller.
我们来做这个
So let's do that.
添加视图控制器中 放到这里
Add view controller. Let's put this right here.
这是常规的prepareForSegue
This is normal prepare for segue here.
我们需要明确是哪个segue
We need to figure out which segue it is
我们这里不能看目标视图控制器
and so we could-- we really can't look at the destination view controller here.
因为添加照片视图控制器可以说是
Because add photo view controller is kind of like part
另外一个视图控制器的视图的一部分
of the view of that other view controller.
关于PhotosByPhotographerMapViewController
So it really can't be looking, it can't know anything
它不知道任何信息
about the photos by photographer map view controller.
不过我们可以看segue的标识符
But what we can do is look at the segue's identifier.
如果segue的标识符是之前我设置的
So if the segue's identifier is what I set there
也就是Do Add Photo
which was do add photo, right?
这是我之前在故事板中设置的
That's what I set it to in the storyboard--
或许这里我们可以这样做
and probably we want to have this be called something
写上UNWIND_SEGUE_IDENTIFIER 像这样
like unwind segue identifier or something like that.
在上面这里定义 复制 #define
We'll put this up here. Copy, pound sign, define.
像这样 这就定义了一个常数
Like that. So I have a nice constant there.
马上我们就会用到这个常数
We're going to need this constant in a second as you'll see.
如果这是unwind 那么我们就希望创建照片
So if this is the unwind, then we want to create that photo.
创建照片需要什么呢
So what do we need to create the photo?
首先 我需要一个ManagedObjectContext
Well, first thing I need is a managed object context.
如果对数据库无能为力 我就创建不了照片
Okay I can't create a photo unless I have a handle on the database.
不过我可以做到 因为self.photographerTakingPhoto
But I do because self dot photographer taking the photo
有一个ManagedObjectContext 我要把这张照片
has a managed object context, so I'm going to put this photo
放到拍照者相同的数据库中 这也正是我要的
in the same database that the photographer's in which is exactly what I want.
这很好
So that's good.
如果这个context不是nil 那么我们就能创建照片
So if that context is not nil, then we can create our photo.
Photo *photo = … 之前还需要导入Photo
So photo star photo equals, and let's import photo.
如何创建照片呢
Okay, so how do we create a photo?
NSEntityDescription insertNewObjectForIdentity…
NS entity description, insert new object for identity,
Photo
photo,
而context是context
and the context is that context.
我这就创建了一张照片
All right I've created a photo!
下面 我只需要设置照片中的所有信息
Now I just need to set everything in the photo.
photo.title = self.titleTextField.text
So photo dot title equals self dot title text field dot text.
错了 删掉方括号
Oops. Get rid of these square brackets.
然后photo.subtitle = self.subtitleTextField.text
All right, and photo dot subtitle equals self dot subtitle title field dot text.
这时 我们就能从那些文本框中抓出文本了
So here's how we are grabbing the text out of those text fields
就像使用标签一样
just using, just like a label, right?
抓取文本属性 这是一个NSString
Just grabbing the text property which is an NS string.
我们还从该照片中获得什么
And what else do we got to get out of this photo?
还有不少信息
Well quite a few other things actually.
我们得到photo.whoTook
We got photo dot who took.
都知道这是什么吧
Everyone know what that is?
photographerTakingPhoto 这就是这里的whoTook
All right, photographer taking the photo, that's who took this thing.
photo.latitude呢
How about photo dot latitude?
我们还没有纬度
Okay, well we don't have the latitude.
我们需要获取纬度 为此 这里我需要添加一些属性
We've got to get that latitude, so to do that I'm going to add some properties here.
我添加了这些属性
Okay so I added these properties.
一个是跟踪位置 在CLLocation中
One is to keep track of our location, in the CL location.
一个是跟踪图像的URL
One is to keep track of the URL of our image.
一个是缩略图
One is our thumbnail.
而且我还说 addedPhoto等于某个东西
And also I'm going to say add photo, added photo equals something.
这个设置为读写
So I'm going to make this one read write and I'm going
而这个设置为只读
to make this one read only over here.
这样这个参数就只能往外出去
So that this is truly an outgoing parameter.
这里面设置为读写
So I'll make it read write here internally.
我需要导入Core Location
So I need to import core location,
因为这里在用Core Location
okay because I'm using core location right here.
我们还要设置这个位置 等下我们就会这样做
Okay and we're going to have to set this location which we'll do in a moment.
不过现在 我们到这里
But in the meantime, let's go here.
这将是self.location.coordinate.latitude
This is going to be self dot location dot coordinate dot latitude.
然后photo.longitude =
And photo out longitude equals
self.location.coordinate.longitude
self dot location dot coordinate dot longitude.
然后我们说photo.imageURL =
And then let's say photo dot image URL equals
self.imageURL absoluteString
self dot image dot URL, absolute string
我们需要实现这个
and we're going to have to implement this.
因为现在 我们的图像只是在那个图像视图中
Because right now our image is just in that image view.
我们需要把它放到磁盘上 并得到一个URL
We're going to have to put it on disk and get a URL to it.
我们需要实现这个
So we'll have to implement that.
然后我们有photo.thumbnailURL =
And then we got photo dot thumbnail URL equals
这里还是一样的做法 absoluteString
or do the same thing here, absolute string.
最后我们要说
Okay and then finally we're going to say
self.addedPhoto = photo
self dot added photo equals the photo.
在unwind中 在unwind的准备中
So in the unwind, in preparing for the unwind,
我们将照片放入了数据库
we put that photo in the database.
不过这里可能会有问题
Now, there could be a problem here.
如果用户还没有拍照呢
What happens if the user hasn't taken a photo yet?
它们没有点拍照
Okay, they haven't hit take photo.
我不能做这些
Th- I can't do this.
空照片什么意义都没有
Okay a photo of, blank photo makes no sense whatsoever.
这是一个常规的segue准备
So this is a normal segue preparation.
我还可以这样做 BOOL
So I can also do bool
shouldPerformSegueWithIdentifier
should perform segue with the identifier.
用来检查点击时是否应该进行unwind
So this is whether we should do the unwind at all when we click it.
我还是要做相同的事情
So again I'm going to do the same,
如果segue的标识符等于那个UNWIND常数
if segue identifier is that unwind guy.
然后我要检查一些东西
And then I'm just going to check some things
如果没有self.image 那么我就会警告
to make sure things are okay like if not self dot image, then I'm going to complain.
这里我们说 尚未拍照
So let's say no photo taken.
我可以说 否则
Okay or I might say or else
如果self.titleTextField.text length
if self dot title text field dot text length
非 这里我强制要求标题存在
not-- so if, I'll force a title here
这时我也要self alert说 必须有标题
and I'll say self alert title required.
这里叹号好多
Too many exclamation points there.
否则 返回YES
Otherwise, we'll return yes.
这两种情况下我们都应返回NO 不应segue
In both of these cases we want to return no that we should not segue.
在尝试这些segue之前 我们先来看这个
Now before we go on and try all this segueing stuff, let's talk about this okay?
看到这个方法了吗 alert 我还没有定义
See this little method alert which I haven't defined yet?
让我们来实现这个
Let's go ahead and implement that.
这对于我们讨论警告视图是个不错的例子
This is a good aside for us to talk about alert view here.
我们这样 (void)alert:(NSString *)msg
So let's do void alert NS string, message.
我们这里会显示一个警告框 给出这个消息
What we want to do here is put up an alert that says whatever that message is.
如何做到呢
So how do we do that?
UIAlertVIew alloc init这一长串
UI alert view, alloc init this long thing.
标题是什么
What's the title?
我们正在添加照片 不妨设这个为警告框
Well, we're adding a photo so we'll say the title of this alert.
顶部的标题
That's the little title at the top.
不是消息 而是顶部标题
Not the message but the title at the top.
添加照片
Say add photo.
消息则是我们想在这里显示的消息
The message is the message that we want to give right here.
委托 这个我设为不要委托
Delegate, I'm going to make this one have no delegate.
等下再来看委托
Show it with a delegate in a minute.
取消按钮
Cancel button.
没有取消
There's no cancel.
唯一的按钮是OK
And the only button is okay.
我创建了这个警告视图 下面我要显示它
So I've created this alert view, now I'm going to show it.
都理解了吗
Everyone understand that?
这里不过是显示
So that's just showing.
我们来看看这个
So let's go ahead and take a look at this.
看看这里怎么了
What have we got here?
抱歉 这里只是一个标识符
Oh sorry, this is just the identifier.
看看还有什么
Yeah what else have we got here?
这里是否则 返回super should…
Okay this else return super should okay?
这里是说 如果这不是我们的标识符
That's if we don't, if it's not our identifier,
而是别的 那么我们就用super
it's some other one, then we'll do super.
让我们这样做
So let's do that.
进入照片
All right so we'll go to photos.
到这里
We go here.
下面尝试unwind
Now let's try to unwind.
尚未拍照
No photo taken.
shouldPerform方法给出了警告
So did our should perform put up an alert?
尚未拍照
No photo taken.
看到了吗 这很好
See that? So that's good.
我们尝试unwind 这样unwind就快搞定了
So we're trying to unwind so we're getting closer to unwinding.
我们还需要得到照片 并确保设置了标题
We still have to get an image and we have to make sure we set our title.
我们很近了
So we're getting closer.
这里我还想讲点题外话
I'm going to take another little aside
也就是使用委托来进行警告
to show you doing an alert with a delegate.
如果应用程序中
What if I had something in my application
我得到了一个致命错误 致命警告 这会怎样
which was a fatal error, fatal alert.
这个警告很糟糕 我需要立刻取消
So this is some alert that's so bad I got to cancel right away.
直接取消
Just do cancel.
如何实现这个
How would I implement that?
我可以使用和这里相同的警告
Well, I would do the same alert that I'm doing here.
但委托不为nil
But instead of having the delegate be nil,
而为self 这样我就能在用户点OK时
I'm going to have the delegate be self so that I can find out when the user clicks okay.
直接取消掉
And when they click okay, I'm going to cancel.
我要消掉自己
I'm going to dismiss myself.
要做这个 我需要是一个UIAlertViewDelegate
So to do this, I need to be a UI alert view delegate.
然后 我要实现alertView
And then I'm going to implement the alert view.
这里有不少 我要用的是
I'm going to do the one dis- you can see there's a few here--
didDismissWithButtonIndex
did dismiss with button index. That's the one I'm going to do.
这里我只有一个按钮 因此无需考察按钮索引
And I only have this one button so I didn't even need to look at the button index.
我知道这里我需要取消
I know that in this case I want to cancel.
我没有将自己设置为这个的委托
Now I didn't set myself as the delegate for this one,
因此对于常规警告我不打算取消
so I'm not going to cancel for a normal alert.
只在致命警告时 我才会取消
Only for a fatal alert am I going to cancel.
什么叫致命呢
Now what would be fatal?
这里什么情况才会致命呢
What kind of things would be fatal in this?
如果我的设备没有摄像头
Well, what if my device has no camera?
这就是致命了
Okay that's fatal.
没有摄像头 这些东西都只是浪费时间
It's just a waste of time to have this thing up if my device has no camera.
另外 Photomania的本质是照片位置
Or, since this PhotoMania is fundamentally locations
如果我无法获知位置 那也会没有意义
of photos, what if I can't get the location?
或许用户不允许我获得位置信息
Okay the user maybe doesn't allow me to get the location.
因此 我们这里再加个方法 canAddPhoto
So let's go ahead and put a method up here called can add photo.
这里需要导入一些东西
We've got to import some stuff here.
canAddPhoto会检查是否能添加照片
So this can add photo method is going to check some
这些致命错误包括 我有没有摄像头
of these fatal errors like do I have a camera available?
我问UIImagePickerController 有没摄像头可用
I'm asking the UI image picker controller, is there a camera available?
我还要确保我能得到一张图像
I'm also making sure I can get an image
一般你可能不会检查这个
which really you usually don't have to check this.
多数时候 你只需检查能否录视频
Mostly you're checking this to see if it'll do video.
所有摄像头都能拍摄图像
All cameras can do image,
这里我就演示一下这些检查
but just to show you what it looks like to check it.
然后我还要检查位置管理器
And then I'm also going to check my location manager
确保我的授权状态不是受限
to make sure my authorization status is not restricted.
也就是说 我的授权状态要么是允许 要么是拒绝
So that means my authorization status is either you're authorized, or denied.
为什么这里我只检查受限呢
Now why am I only checking restricted here?
因为这是致命错误
Because this is going to be a fatal error.
成为致命错误的情况
It's only going to be fatal
只包括用户无法控制app能否找到其位置的情况
if the user can't control whether my app can find its location.
用户无法设置这些 这就是致命错误
All right, they can't go to settings and set it, so it's fatal.
后面我还会检查 用户是否只是拒绝
Later I'll check to see if they've just denied it
我会建议用户回到设置
and I'm going to suggest to them they go back to settings
取消拒绝 这样它就可以工作了
and undeny it and then it'll work.
这并不是致命错误
So it's not a fatal error in that case.
这就是这里只考虑受限这一状态的原因
So that's the difference why we're doing restricted here, okay?
如果所有这些都没问题 那就很好了
So if any, if all this is true, then we're good to go.
我们可以拍照
We can take a photo.
否则我们就无法拍照
Otherwise, we can't take a photo.
下面 在我们的viewDidAppear中
So now let's, in our view will appear or view did appear--
super viewDidAppear
super, view did appear--
我要说 if ([[self class] canAddPhoto])
I'm going to say if self class can add photo--
这里应该是非 如果我不能添加照片
actually I'm going to say if not-- if I can't add a photo,
那么 我就要self fatalAlert说
then I'm going to self fatal alert
抱歉 本设备无法添加照片
sorry this device cannot add a photo.
注意 我在致命错误中并没有说
Notice I'm not saying anything in this fatal error like
你无权获得你的位置信息
you are not authorized to do, get your location
因为用户对此无能为力
because there's nothing they can do about it.
如果没有摄像头
If they have no camera or they can't do it, they can't go
用户不能去找一个摄像头
out of camera or, you know, do something
权限受限用户也没辙
about their being restricted from doing the location.
所以这里我也不需要建议用户做任何事
They can't do anything so I'm not going to suggest they do anything.
我只打算说 抱歉 你做不了这个
I'm just going to say sorry, you can't do it.
当然 我也可以说 抱歉 本设备不能拍照
I could imagine maybe saying here, sorry this device cannot have a photo
因为你没有摄像头
because you have no camera.
但我肯定不打算说 因为你无法获得位置信息
I definitely wouldn't want to say because you cannot get your location.
或者 如果我想说这个
Or if I do say that, I want
我可以说 同系统管理员联系 尝试获得权限
to say contact your system administrator or something like that to get yourself there.
你知道的 不过我只说
It's, you know, but here I'm just going
抱歉 你无法拍照
to say sorry you can't take a photo, and it's going
这是致命的 因此我会立刻取消
to be fatal so I'm going to immediately drop out of there.
我们来看看这个
So let's take a look at that.
进入照片 然后到这里
All right there's photos, and I'm going to bring this up.
果然 这里显示出"本设备无法拍照"
And sure enough sorry, this device cannot add a photo.
为什么 因为这是模拟器
Why? Because it's the simulator.
模拟器无法添加照片
The simulator cannot add a photo.
这很好地告诉了我 我无法拍照
So it's properly telling me I can't add a photo
如果我点OK 它就会取消
and if I click okay, cancel.
这是致命错误
Okay so fatal error.
下面 我们将继续后面的内容
Okay so now we're going to continue, we're going to switch
转到一个可以拍照的设备上
over and do it on a device where we actually can do this stuff.
要做到这个 下面我们需要用到位置管理器
But to do that, the next thing we want to do is location manager.
我从没演示过如何使用位置这些
So I never showed you how to do the location stuff
这里是一个很好的例子
and so this is a good example of how to show that.
我想把这个self.location设为某个东西
So I want to set this self dot location to something.
因为现在 它是nil
Because right now it's going to be nil, right?
因为我刚创建了这个属性 从未设置它
Because I just created that property and I never set it,
而这里我在看它
and then here I'm looking at it.
我们的经纬度都是0
So our latitude and longitude would be zero so we're going
我们可能位于非洲西面的海洋中
to be somewhere out in the ocean somewhere west of Africa or something.
或许还有海盗在追我们
Probably have pirates after us over there.
我们不想这样
So we don't want to do that.
我们要设置self.location
We want to set this self.location.
怎么做呢
So how are we going to do that?
要做到这个 我需要一个位置管理器
Well, to do that I need a location manager.
找个地方放这些东西
So let's find a good place to put all this.
放到下面这里
Let's put it down here.
我需要一个位置管理器
So I need a location manager and I,
为了提高速度 我准备了这些
for speed here I have this to show you how to do that.
我只需要添加这个属性
So I'm just going to add this property right?
CLLocationManager *locationManager
CL location manager, location manager,
记得吧 我们会要求
remember this is the thing we ask
这个东西开始给我们位置的更新
to start giving us updates on the location.
然后我要惰性实例化它
And then I'm going to lazily instantiate it.
这里 惰性实例化
Here it is here, lazy instantiation.
如果没有创建 我将alloc init
If we haven't created one, then I'm going to alloc init it.
我将把self设为委托
I'm going to set myself as the delegate.
这里有警告 因为我还没有说我是哪类委托
Obviously warning because I haven't said that I'm that kind of delegate yet.
然后我要把精度设为最佳
And then I'm going to set my accuracy to best.
为什么设为最佳呢
Why am I doing best?
因为我想准确知道这张照片拍自哪里
Because I want to know exactly where this photo was taken?
我只是模态的 我只会在屏幕上待几秒钟
And I'm modal anyway so I'm only going to be on screen for a few moments.
只是找到我在哪 并不会用掉很多电量
I'm not going to use up the whole battery just finding out where I am.
然后这里 我们设置位置管理器
And then here we set the location manager.
然后这是我要使用的委托方法
And then here's the delegate method I'm going to use.
我是委托 我将获取委托方法
I'm the delegate, so I'm going to get the delegate method.
它叫locationManager didUpdateLocations
It's called location manager did update locations.
它会给我一个数组 其中是它找到的所有位置
It gives me an array of all the locations it's found
自该方法上次调用这条消息以来
since the last time it called this message, this method.
我将抓取最后一个
And I'm just going to grab the last one.
最后一个总会是最新的一个 最准确的一个
The last one is always the most current one, the most up to date, the most accurate.
这里我们要的总会是它
That's the one you always want there.
想找当前位置就该这么做
If you're just trying to get your current location.
我将把这个放到self.location
And I'm just going to put that in self dot location so that
这样一来 到这里就会是正确的位置
when I pop it in here it'll be the right location.
这还没完
Now, we're not done here
因为这个位置管理器 我们需要开启它
because this location manager, we have to start it up.
记得吧 创建一个位置管理器…
Okay remember, just because you create a location manager--
让我先来处理这个委托
let me go ahead and do this delegate thing first,
让我自己成为CLLocationManagerDelegate
make myself be a CL location manager delegate.
我需要开启它
I need to start it up.
在哪做呢
And where am I going to start it up?
在viewDidAppear中
I'm going to start it up in view did appear.
我要说 否则 因为这里是不能添加照片的情况
So I'm going to say else-- okay this is I can't add a photo.
否则 我要说 self.locationManager
So else, I'm going to say self dot location manager--
这会惰性实例化它 开始更新位置
that's going to lazily instantiate it starts updating location.
这就会开始向我发送位置的委托方法
And that's going to start sending me those delegate methods of my location, all right?
也许马上 它就会发送一个很不准确的给我
It's probably going to send me one right away that's pretty inaccurate,
例如基于wifi的 或是别的什么
like WiFi based or something,
然后它可能会发送另一个使用GPS的消息
then it'll probably send me another one with GPS
如果我在外面 可以和卫星通讯的话
if I'm outside or I can, you know, see the satellites.
这可能会多于一个 这没问题
So it might send me more than one. That's okay.
随时间推移 我希望它持续发送越来越准确的信息
I want it to keep sending me more and more accurate ones as time goes on.
这样做时 你几乎总要在viewWillDisappear中
If you do this, you almost always, in view will disappear,
将这个关闭掉
want to turn this back off.
这里问题其实并不大
Now it's not that huge a deal here
因为这个是模态方式present的
because this thing is presented modally.
这里是停止更新位置
Oops, stop updating location.
这是模态方式present的 因此当这个unwind时
This is presented modally and so when this thing unwinds,
它会从堆中被释放
it's going to get released from the heap.
从堆中被释放时
And when it gets released from the heap,
这个位置管理器也会被释放 并停止更新
this location manager's going to get released and it's going to stop updating.
因此这里问题不大
So it's really not that big a deal,
不过有些情况下
but if for some reason we ever figured out how
这个会以非模态方式呈现出来
to make this thing not be modal, put it up in a non modal way,
我们希望养成好习惯
we just want to be in the good habit
每次开启这个时 都要再找地方将它关闭
of every time we turn this thing on, turn it off somewhere.
哪怕它会自动被从堆中丢出来
Even if it's, you know, turns it off right before it gets thrown out of the heap.
总记得关掉它
Still, turn it off.
使用位置更新代价很大
Using location updates is expensive.
这个还在时我们可以运行它
Fine to run while this thing is up,
但最后 我们需要确保将它关闭了
but we want to make sure we turn it off.
好 下面再来看还有什么要做
Okay let's go ahead and, let's see what else can we do here?
好 让我们把这两个方法丢入到图像URL和缩略图URL
Yeah, let's go ahead and throw these two methods into image URL and thumbnail URL.
这里对于图像URL和缩略图URL
So all I need to do here with the image URL and thumbnail URL
我只需要把图像视图中的图像放到磁盘上
is I'm just going to take the image that's in my image view, put it on disk,
然后返回URL
and return the URL.
放到磁盘上的哪里呢
Where am I going to put it on disk?
放到一个随机命名的文件中
I'm just going to put it in a randomly named file.
随机取个名字
I'm just going to pick a name, I'm going to pick,
名字将是某个参考日期之后的秒数
the name is going to be the number of seconds since some reference date in
参考日期可以是2001这些
2001 or something like that.
这是唯一的
That's pretty unique.
除非两个设备完全同时使用
It's not likely, I mean unless somehow you did two different
而这是在iCloud中
devices identically and this was over iCloud,
这时就可能会有冲突 不过我们就这样做
you could conceivably get a conflict there but we're just going to do that.
或许有更好的办法 反正这里
Probably better ways but we're going
我们将创建图像URL和缩略图URL 放到下面这里
to create both the image URL and the thumbnail URL. Let's put those down here.
图像URL NSURL imageURL是这样的
So the image URL, NS URL, image URL looks like this.
这是方法的getter
Okay so this is the getter for that method,
我将按惰性方式创建文件
so I'm going lazily create that file.
一旦有人想要它的URL
As soon as someone wants the URL for it,
我就会创建文件
I'm going to go create the file.
换言之 如果!_imageURL
So if not image URL-- in other words,
我就会惰性实例化它
I'm going to lazily instantiate it.
且我们有图像
And we have an image,
显然 没有图像 我们就无法创建文件
okay because we can't create the file if we don't have an image,
不过如果有图像 我们就会这样做
but if we do have the image then we'll do it.
让我们这样做 我们说NSURL
Let's do this, let's say NS URL,
url = self uniqueDocumentURL
URL equals self unique document URL.
这将是文档目录下唯一的URL
Okay so this is just going to be a unique URL in my documents directory.
我写到了这里 你们有时间可以看
I have that one here for you, you can look at it at your leisure.
你们已经知道如何做这些东西
It just does, you know how to do all these things already
我没必要再讲一次
so there's no use going over them again.
我有了这个唯一的URL
So I got this unique URL.
如果这能成功
If that was successful,
那么我就要从图像视图中获取图像数据
then I'm going to get the image data out of my image view
我打算通过这个很酷的函数来做到这一点
and I'm going to do that through this kind of cool function,
UIImageJPEGRepresentation
UI image jpeg representation.
它的参数是一个UIImage
It will take a UI image
返回的是NSData 带有它的JPEG
and give you back an NS data with a Jpeg of that thing.
很酷 不是吗
Pretty cool, huh?
不是所有图像都能这样做
Not all images can do this but,
不过摄像头拍摄的图像都没问题
you know, the kind of images that we load from the camera can, for example.
这将是self.image
So this would be self dot image,
然后这是压缩程度
and then this is how much you want to compress it,
我希望压缩尽可能少
and I'm going to compress it as little as possible.
因为我希望照片跟刚拍的时候差别尽可能小
Because I want the image to be as close to what you took of the camera as possible.
我不希望压缩毁掉图片的原样
I don't want any compression artifacts or any of that stuff
因为这就是你实际拍的照片
because this is the actual image you took.
有了这个以后 我想说
So now that I have this, I'm going to say if I'm able
如果我能把这个写出 那就写到URL
to write this thing out, write to URLs.
writeToURL是一个USData方法 我将指定URL
So write to URL is an NS data method and I'm going to specify that URL,
YES 这里我要按原子方式来
and yes I'm going to do it atomically
意味着会写入到一个临时文件
which means it's going to write it to a temporary file,
删除已有的 在一个原子事务中移过来
delete any existing one, move it over in one atomic transaction
如果手机在过程中崩溃
so if the phone crashes in the middle, you won't get,
旧文件就还会在那里
you'll still have an old file if it were still there.
如果它成功做到了 那么这就是图像URL
If it successfully does that, then now this is the image URL.
记住 这是图像URL的getter 我在设置这个
Remember this is the getter for image URL so I'm setting that.
现在 我们可以返回图像URL
And now we can return our image URL.
每次你要图像URL时
Now one thing is, every time you ask for the image URL,
我都会把它写出到磁盘
I'm writing it out to disk.
不是每次 而是首次要的时候
Well not every time but the first time you ask for it.
我需要小心 如果有人把照片换了
I better be careful here if someone changes the image,
我就需要重新生成这个URL
I'm going to have to regenerate this URL.
我还需要从磁盘上删除文件
I also want to delete that file off of disk.
这里我要说 如果有人将图像
So here I'm going to say, if anyone sets the image
设置为新图片 我要说NSFileManager
to something new, I'm going to say NS file manager,
defaultManager
default manager,
removeItemAtURL: 我们的imageURL
remove item at URL our image URL.
注意这里我没有调用self.imageURL
Notice I'm not calling self dot image URL here
因为那会创建文件
because that would create the file.
这里有些奇特
So this is a little bit weird.
我说过 除了setter和getter里面
I told you never use underbar
都不要使用带下划线的
in anything but a setter or a getter.
这里我违反了自己说的 不过这是出于性能考虑
I'm violating that but it's, you know, kind of for performance reasons here
我们不关心这里有没有错误
and we don't care if there's an error.
如果它不能删除 它就不能删除
If it couldn't delete it, it couldn't delete it.
而且我还要将imageURL设为nil
And also I'm going to set my image URL to nil
以后再有人问
so that the next time someone asks,
因为我有一张新图片
because I have a new image,
以后再有人问 它就会重新生成
the next time someone asks, it'll regenerate.
我要对缩略图做完全相同的事情
So I'm going to do the exact same thing for the thumbnail.
我创建了这个文件
I created this file here.
我要拖入一点category
I'm going to drag in a little category
这是我之前创建的
that I created
使用了上周五辅导课上的一些代码
using some of the code from last Friday's section
还有一些我写的代码 在这里
and also some of the little code that I wrote. So here it is right here.
拖入这里
Put it in here.
到这里来 这样你们就能看到我在做什么
Oops, let's go here so you can see what I'm doing.
把这个放到这里
Going to put this right here.
这段代码很简单
This code is quite simple.
它只有两个方法
It just has two methods.
一个是取图像 并获得调整尺寸后的新图像
One takes the image and gets a new image by resizing it.
缩略图就是这个了
That's what we want for a thumbnail.
而这个应用了一个过滤器 基于周五辅导课上的内容
And this one applies a filter based on what we saw at Friday's section.
没上周五辅导课的人 可能看不懂这段代码
So if you miss Friday's section you won't understand this code,
上了的人肯定知道
but if you were there you will.
这段代码很简单 使用drawInRect
And this is pretty straightforward code using draw in rect
还有这个GraphicsBeginImageContextWithOption
and this nice graphics begin image context with option
你们可以离线看看这些
so you can look at that offline as well.
下面回到这里
And so now let's go back here,
有了这个以后… 我到哪里了
and now that I have that, let u- where was I?
我来找找
Let's find this thing.
下面吧
It's way down here.
这里
Here it is.
我们获得缩略图 缩略图使用图像相同的URL
So we've got the thumbnail, so the thumbnail uses the same URL as the image
不过加上了.thumbnail
but adds dot thumbnail to it
然后缩放了 其它都完全相同
and then scales it and then does exactly the same thing.
这是缩略图
So now thumbnail,
我们要对缩略图做相同的事
so we want to do the same thing here for the thumbnail.
我们需要删除缩略图文件 我们还要self.thumbnail
We better remove our thumbnail file and we want to self dot thumbnail.
严格来讲 这不是必需的 不过这里就这样
That's not strictly necessary but we'll do it.
现在 我们有了缩略图URL和图像URL
Okay, so now that we have thumbnail URL and image URL,
上面这个照片创建就能完整地创建照片了
this photo creation up here will be able to fully create the photo.
我们还没有摄像头 不过最后
Now we don't have the camera, but I want to end this thing
我打算演示一下目前的进展
by showing you this working so far.
我打算拖入一个图像 一朵小花
So I'm going to drag an image, a little flower--
这朵花我们之前就看到过
this is the flower we saw earlier in the quarter--
我打算把这朵小花当成我们的照片
and I'm going to make this little flower be our photo, okay?
我打算在viewDidLoad中这样做
So I'm just going to do that right here in view did load of this guy.
viewDidLoad
View did load.
super viewDidLoad
Super view did load and I'm going
然后是self.image = UIImage imageNamed
to say self dot image equals UI image image named
flower.jpeg
flower dot jpeg.
这里我要讲讲我刚做的事 这很酷
This is an opportunity to show you another cool thing that we, I just did.
你们看到 我将文件拖入到Photomania的顶层
What you see, I dragged the file right into my top level of PhotoMania
然后我可以使用imageNamed这些直接访问它
and then I can access it directly using something like image named.
你并不一定要把文件放到asset中
So you don't actually have to put things in that asset,
你可以放到顶层 然后像这样访问它们
so you can put them right in the top level if you want and access them that way.
好 但愿… 哦 这不行
All right, so hopefully-- oops, this is not going to work
因为我们需要用真正的设备
because we need to be on a real device.
这里是iPad和iPhone模拟模式
There we go. I've got this iPad and iPhone simulation mode here.
好 到My Photos里面
All right so we'll go to my photos.
这里显示了我的所有照片 我一张都没有
Here's showing all my photos. I don't have any yet.
点相机按钮
We'll press the little camera.
这是相机拍摄的照片
Here's our photo that we took with our camera.
真正的拍照周三再讲 这里就用了一张图像
We'll do that on Wednesday so for now we got photo.
我们可以按完成
We could actually hit done here.
看看会怎样
Watch what happened if we hit done.
它说 必需有标题
It says title required.
记得shouldPerform方法吗 这很好 我们需要这个
Remember we had that should perform so that's good that it requires that.
我们把这个称作Flower
So we'll call this flower
然后是副标题 Pretty
and then we'll have a little subtitle, pretty.
这就好了
So we're ready to go.
点完成 它就会unwind 然后创建照片
Now we hit done, it unwinds, it creates it.
它找到了我们的位置
It found our location.
点它 我们会看到缩略图
If we click on it, we see it's got a thumbnail.
我们可以点击查看照片
We can click to see the photo.
这就是我们的照片
Here's our photo, etcetera.
明白了吗
Got all that?
好 周三 我们将继续这个 讲解实际拍照
Okay, so on Wednesday we will continue by actually getting the photo in here.
我还会演示动作表单
I'll also show you an action sheet.
我们将使用过滤那些
We'll use that filtering thing
创建出过滤照片用的动作表单
to put an action sheet up that filters our photo.
有问题的可以来提
If you have questions I'm here.
更多内容 请访问我校官网stanford.edu
> For more, please visit us at Stanford.edu.